You know, America's 250th birthday is
coming up. That's going to be a big
cake. And now who's who's even going to
blow out the candles? I wonder. Probably
maybe Thomas Jefferson will come down
from the clouds and huff and puff a few
out. Maybe Betsy Ross or Frederick
Douglas. I don't know. Somebody is going
to come on down and just huff and puff
them cake candles out. Happy 250th
America. And an iconic summer like this
deserves an iconic drink. I'm talking
about Mountain Dew. Yep. An American
original. From their beginnings in the
foothills of Tennessee. Yeah, that's
where they started. To the biggest
Fourth of July yet, the refreshing
citrus kick of Mountain Dew is the
perfect companion to your American
summer adventures. USA, baby. And you
know, I get that taste of Mountain Dew
in me and it just oh, just makes my
ankles start talking to each other. God,
I love it. Enjoy the refreshing kick of
Mountain Dew, an American original.
Tasting great since 48. Look for
Americ.com.
That's mountaind.com.
Today's guest is an author. Uh he's a
speaker. He's a former CIA officer who's
also known for being a whistleblower in
the CIA's use of torture. He has a new
book coming out called The Ultimate
Guide to CIA Skills, Tactics, and
Techniques. Today's guest is Mr. John
Kiryaku. Shine
on me
and I will find a song. I'll be singing.
>> Yeah. I applied for a presidential
pardon.
>> You you applied for a uh a presidential
pardon?
>> Yeah. Yeah. In fact, I I brought a
couple of letters. I
>> I hope you don't
>> Long as you don't meet me. If I sign
him, it's not going to help anything.
I'm just [laughter] telling you that.
Oh, okay. I was gonna ask if I was gonna
ask if you thought it would be helpful.
I got uh
>> Did you really?
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, okay. Dang. I was joking.
>> Oh, no, no, no. I'm talking to Tulsi
Gabbert on Friday. Did I tell you that?
>> Oh, nice. Her husband just went into
surgery today. I saw me with her
yesterday.
>> She's great.
>> Yeah, Tulsi Gabbard. She seems um she's
there's just something about her that
seems genuine to me
>> and and that's why they tried to destroy
her. Is that is that what you think is
going on with her right now?
>> That's why the Democrats tried to
destroy her. I really do.
>> But even right now, I mean, she's just
taken a leave. I know it's for her
husband's health.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> Oh, yeah. Headed into surgery this
morning.
>> Oh, is that what it says?
>> Yeah. She tweeted or she uh
>> Instagram. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Do you think cuz she's kind of
like And she just took a break. She took
a complete break from politics.
>> Yeah.
You remember when she was running as a
Democrat,
>> every time she would inch up in the
polls, the DNC would change the rules
for participating in the next debate.
>> So, they would do it just one or two
percentage points out of her reach every
single time because they were threatened
by her message. She just wouldn't get
with their program.
>> She's always seemed very um like she has
her own
>> Oh, she was definitely independent.
>> Independent. That's what it is. She's
always seemed very independent. Um well,
they did the same thing with Bernie
Sanders. They did exactly the same thing
with Bernie Sanders.
>> So, I guess what my my question would be
like, you know, and I pro I I can't
remember if I asked Bernie this or not,
but why would you stay in a party that
you know at a certain point is not
>> that's cheating you? Yes. And you know,
the Democrats did something in um after
the 1972 election, which I think people
don't pay anywhere near enough attention
to.
Nobody at the DNC wanted George McGovern
to be the 1972 nominee. He was the most
popular at the time, especially among
young people, but he was um he was the
weakest nationwide and he ended up
losing 49 states. But,
you know, it's a party of the people,
right? If the people want George
McGovern as the nominee, then George
McGovern should be the nominee. And they
didn't let him become the nominee. No,
they let him become the nominee and then
as soon as he lost the race, they
instituted this this thing called
superdelegates.
So if you are a member of the house, a
member of the Senate, a governor, a a
lieutenant governor, a state party
director, a state committee chairman,
you're automatically made a delegate to
the convention. Well, there are like
1500 of them.
>> And so you end up with situations like
West Virginia and Wyoming where Bernie
Sanders beats Hillary Clinton in both
states and Hillary Clinton wins
literally every delegate
>> from those states. Wow. Like, how's that
fair? So, wait, explain that to me a
little bit better because I want to get
down on this. And George McGovern was a
major reason Democrats later created
superdelegates. After McGovern's 1972
nomination and landslide general
election loss, party leaders wanted a
way to give more influence to
experienced officials and reduce the
chance that a highly activist primary
electorate would produce another nominee
they saw as too extreme. So, you're
saying the people believed in this guy?
Oh, yeah. even though he lost, the
people believed in him, but the party
and whoever that is uh didn't want it to
be like just a like a populist vote.
They didn't want just the people to have
the choice.
>> They wanted to go back to the days with
the smoke filled back rooms with the
party bosses choosing who's going to be
the nominee.
>> And if they put it more on the shoulders
of just the de the superdelegates,
>> then they could control [clears throat]
fewer. It was fewer people they had to
control.
>> Exactly. Exactly. I am proud to say in
1983 I was a sophomore in college. I was
the speakers committee chairman. I was
the whole committee of the George
Washington University College Democrats
in the days when I was a Democrat. And I
saw a little blurb in the Washington
Post saying, "Hey, remember George
McGovern? Uh, he's thinking of running
for president again." So I wrote him a
letter. I said, "Hey, I read that you're
thinking of running for president again.
We have a fantastic theater here at the
school. we can do all the leg work.
Ready-made volunteers. My phone rings a
few days later, wakes me up, and it's
George McGovern. Yeah.
>> And he says, "Can I see that theater?" I
said, "Of course." So, he comes over to
school and uh we walk over to the
theater. Nobody recognized him.
>> And uh he said, "Yeah, the theater's
perfect." And there's like a cutout for
cameras and it was perfect. So, he says,
"Don't tell anybody, but I am going to
run for president again."
>> And this is after the 72 loss.
>> Yeah. This is uh yeah 11 years after the
72 loss Reagan is president.
>> Okay.
>> So um we put out a press release major
announcement by Senator George McGovern
on such and such a date George
Washington University in the Marvin
Theater and uh and packed the place and
it was on the news. Um and here's what a
sweet guy he was. He did the
announcement and brought important
people with him like uh Mo Ud Doll.
Remember Mo Udall? He ran for president
in 76. He was a congressman from uh
Arizona. And uh there he is. And then um
Cliff Robertson, the Academy
Award-winning actor, and his wife uh
Dena Merrill. Yeah. They both came.
>> So he brought some heisters.
>> He brought his own influencers.
>> Yeah. And uh and Frank Manowitz, who had
been Robert Kennedy Senior's U press
secretary, was was Senator McGovern's
press secretary.
>> You must have been geeked, huh?
>> Oh, yeah. I was I mean it was
incredible. And then he makes the
announcement. He shakes everybody's hand
and he invites me back to his apartment
and his wife made tuna sandwiches.
>> Nice. Just the loveliest people. He
ended up, crazy as it sounds, coming in
third.
>> Walter [snorts] Montdale won. Gary Hart
came in second and McGovern came in
third.
>> And that was for the Democratic Party.
>> Yeah.
>> Wow.
>> And they kept saying, "Drop out George.
Drop out George. Drop out George."
Because he was pulling young people. I
remember um Jesse Jackson when he ran,
he was very close, right? Wasn't he the
populist choice kind of?
>> Yes, he was the populist choice. 1984
and 1988.
>> He was very much so.
>> And cuz I remember we had I think we had
a sign for him like, [snorts] you know,
our family was always like, you know,
pretty,
you know, liberal and hopeful and new
ideas, right?
>> That's how mine was.
>> Yeah. But like but not but not like
ethereal at the same time. Not like
unrealistic, right? Not unrealistic, but
we were hopeful. You know what I'm
saying? Um, but yeah. Didn't Jesse
Jackson and did they just not service
him or what happened with Jesse Jackson?
Yeah, they let him kind of
self-destruct. See, it says here he won
11 contests. He did very, very well in
88, but he was never a Democratic party
insider. Got it. The insiders were not
going to let him have that nomination.
>> That's what they do. And the Republicans
don't have such a system.
You don't think so?
>> No, they don't have superdelegates.
Which means then an insurgent candidate
like like a Donald Trump can win a
nomination.
>> I see. But it's less likely to happen in
the Democratic party.
>> Much less likely to happen
>> because of superdelegates. Wow. I didn't
realize that only one party had those.
>> Al Franken
because Hold on before you move forward
on Al Franken. So, but uh didn't Jesse
Jackson win a few like in a row? Like he
was
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. He was on a roll.
>> He was all he was building momentum.
>> Uhhuh. And they were like, "Yeah, we're
going to put the brakes on this."
>> And when they say, "We are going to put
the brakes on this." Who is the we? Is
it just
>> It's the It's the state committee
chairman who make up the Democratic
National Committee.
>> Got it. But it's just the insiders. It's
like the the money talking whoever those
like it's the smoky backroom.
>> This congresswoman from Florida, her
name escapes me. Three names. But
anyway, she was the head of what was it?
>> No, she was the head of the DNC
in 20 Debbie Wasserman Schultz. Thank
you very much. Debbie Wasserman Schultz
>> um
>> gave Hillary Clinton's campaign all the
debate questions
>> before the debate.
>> Remember that.
>> But Bernie didn't get the questions.
>> Crazy.
>> It's crazy. It's fixed. Yeah. I think we
all know what happened at this point.
Yeah. Um
>> the fix was in.
>> But the fix was in. It's just it's a it
it starts to make you feel like okay
that the the regular person like what
you really want the even the idea of
that it used to feel real and it doesn't
feel real anymore. And that I think is
one of the scariest things happening in
America right now. You're like
>> it used to feel hopeful and now it feels
um
>> it's will we survive? It feel there's
something else. It's not a hope. I don't
even know if it it's somewhat of a fear,
but it's more of an uncertainty. But
America used to feel like this hopeful
thing like we're building this thing
that's going to that that means
something that we're going to pass on to
our uh children and that um and that
could possibly stand the test of time.
And when that when something like that
[snorts] you believe in something like
that,
>> it makes your day-to-day
uh interactions and your interaction
with your country and uh it it makes
that all more meaningful to you. So you
show up for it differently. Um we're
sitting here with John
>> Kiryaku.
>> Kiryaku, uh thank you so much for coming
in.
>> Thank you for the invitation. I love the
show. I've seen so many clips of you uh
recalling stories from your time in the
CIA. Is having a a good memory a
requirement uh for the job?
>> Oh yeah.
>> Is it really?
>> Oh my gosh. Yes.
>> Is it a requirement?
>> It's actively encouraged. I had a
station chief one time who gave me the
biggest compliment.
>> You had a what one time?
>> A station chief.
>> Okay.
>> So I was doing a I was doing
[clears throat] an operation in the
Middle East, but I was doing it from
headquarters. The station chief called
me. We were friends from our training
days. And he said, "Listen, we recruited
a double agent out here. He's insisting
on meeting with the chief, but it's just
too dangerous for me to meet with him
cuz he doesn't know that we know he's
working for the bad guys."
>> Got it.
>> Can you come out here every month and
meet with him and pretend to be me? And
I said, "Sure." So, I did. To make a
long story short, I would do the meeting
and then go straight to the airport and
fly back to Washington. There was a
midnight flight.
>> Mhm.
>> And um I would write the cable, the
reporting cable from headquarters
instead of writing it from the station
and then sending it to headquarters. I'd
write it from headquarters and send it
to the station. And the great compliment
he gave me was he said, "Your memory is
so good. You remember so many details
that when I read the cables, I feel like
I'm in the room watching it go down." M
>> and I said that is exactly what I'm
going for.
>> Yeah. I've always been proud of of being
able to do that.
>> But it wasn't a requirement when you uh
when you uh I guess I don't know if you
audition for the CIA, but how do you
>> Yeah, you kind of do. Yeah.
>> What's that process like? Like how do
you get [sighs]
>> extensive? Is it It's changed from when
I joined. When I joined, I was in
graduate school at George Washington
University and I was taking a class
called the psychology of leadership. And
the class was about
why foreign leaders make the decisions
that they make. One of the examples that
sticks in my mind is the Yaltta
conference at the end of World War II.
Why was it in Yaltta of all places?
>> I'm not familiar with it. Bring it up.
The Yaltta conference. Uh the World War
II Yeah. um the altar conference was a
World War II meeting of the heads of
government of the United States, UK, and
the Soviet Union to discuss the post-war
reorganization of Germany and Europe.
Okay. Yeah. So Roosevelt, Churchill, and
Stalin, they all met in Yalta.
>> They all met in Yalta, which is really,
really hard to get to. And you can't
just, you know, get in a plane and fly
over the war. The war's still going on,
right? So Roosevelt took a train to to
Norphick, Virginia, then took a boat to
Malta, which took like a week, right?
Back in those days,
>> which is obviously a scop because it
rhymes with Yalta,
>> right? And then he had to go to Cairo
and then Iran and then from Iran to
Yaltta. He was sick. He died a month
later.
>> Wow. So the reason why it was in Yaltta
is because Stalin had a spy in the White
House and the spy told him Roosevelt is
sick. And so Stalin wanted him to be as
weak as possible. When they arrived or
when when the American side arrived,
Roosevelt was exhausted and he wanted to
go to sleep and he
>> but Stalin insisted that the talks begin
immediately.
>> Wow.
>> And so just to be able to go to bed,
Roosevelt gave up Poland.
Look, I'll throw in poll and let's talk
tomorrow.
>> Exactly.
>> Oh yeah, dude. Look, sometimes Yeah.
Sometimes where you show up and you're
like, "Yeah, you can't do it." Yeah. Or
you just say, "Look, yes, take that.
>> That's [laughter] fine. I got You know
what I'm saying? I got to brush my teeth
and lay down for a few minutes." It's
crazy the things you will give up when
you first get somewhere just to get to
your room and unpack. Amen.
>> To urinate.
>> Oh. So I'm in this class and just to be
clear, so they made him go all that way
just because they knew it would weaken
him.
>> Yeah. There it is.
>> So they created a a path that would just
like that would add to him because they
had a spine in the wild.
>> Yeah.
>> President Franklin D. Roosevelt died of
a massive cerebral hemorrhage on April
12th, 1945 at Warm Springs, Georgia,
just 2 months after the Yaltta
conference. While the grueling 7,000mi
trip to the Soviet Union, combined with
his severe underlying cardiovascular
conditions took a significant toll on
his already failing health. Wow. Do you
see what a wellplaced spy can do for
you?
>> That's strategy right there.
>> That is strategy. It's that's the big
leagues right there.
>> That's the big leagues.
>> So, I'm in this class and the the
professor Dr. Gerald Post, eminent
psychiatrist,
uh tells us to um shadow our bosses for
a week, just watch our bosses, spend
each day with them, and then do a
psychological profile on our bosses.
>> And this is when you're at George
Washington University. You're a student,
>> right? He was in grad school. There's
there's Jerry.
>> And what what a great man he was.
>> He died of CO. The poor guy.
>> So, um,
>> so he was murdered,
>> right? Right.
>> Carry on.
>> I'm um I'm working at the United Food
and Commercial Workers Union at the
time.
>> And, uh, I work for this guy. He was a
mean, like angry old school union
organizer, right?
>> Mhm. [clears throat]
>> I was a little bit afraid of him to tell
you the truth. big, strong, mean guy.
And halfway through the week, we got
into an argument and I called him a
racist, which he was.
>> Yeah.
>> And he got so mad he set a stance and he
put up his fist like this and I I put up
my hands thinking, "Dang it, I went too
far this time." And he goes, "My penis
is bigger than yours." And I said,
"What?" And he goes, "My penis is bigger
than yours." I said, "You know what?
You're nuts." And I quit. And I walked
out. So, I went back and I banged out my
paper. I said he was a sociopath with
psychopathic and possibly violent
tendencies. And I I footnoted the whole
thing. It wasn't just John venting on
it,
>> but with a possibly decent wiener on it.
>> You're right. Apparently,
>> you got to put apparently.
[laughter]
>> And so, I get the paper back a week
later. Dr. Post gave me an A and then in
the margin he wrote, "Please see me
after class." So, I go up to him. I
said, "Dr. Post, you wanted to see me."
He says, "Come to my office." the this
classroom was like on the sixth floor
and the office was on the fourth. So I
went down there, he closed the door and
he says, "Look, I'm not really a
professor here. I'm a CIA officer
undercover as a professor here. I'm
looking who for people who would fit
into the CIA's culture. I think you
would fit in. You know, would you like
to join the CIA?" And I said, "Oh, yes,
I would."
>> And so the rest though is up to you. He
It was kind of a long story. I'll skip
it. But he made a couple of calls that
got me deep into the process.
>> Got it. So Mr. Post was your professor.
>> Yes.
>> And you also had this job where you were
under where the where the guy was the
racist guy.
>> Yeah. That was at a union. So I was I
[clears throat] was using that union job
to put myself through grad school.
>> Got it.
>> And then I just I quit and I walked out.
I said, "The guy's dangerous." And I I
guess the way I wrote the paper made him
think that the analysis was concise. It
was to the point and I backed it up with
the facts. So I go through these weird
He sent me across the across the river
to Rosland, Virginia. Uh Arlington,
Virginia. It's a little neighborhood
right across the PTOIC from Washington.
Hold one second. So So he was a he was a
CIA operative. This professor?
[laughter]
>> Yes. Now, when someone's a CIA
operative, but also a professor, are
they an actual professor that then gets
hired?
>> That's a great question.
>> Like, which is first?
>> That's a great question. It's usually
that they're a CIA operative first and
then they get hired as a professor. What
he did is illegal today. Got it.
>> So, in 1993, Congress passed the Equal
Employment Opportunity Act,
>> the EEOC, which made this illegal. So,
um,
now it's very like not sexy. You just go
to www.cia.gov
and click apply,
>> right?
>> Different.
>> It's different.
>> It's a little easier.
>> Back then it was, you know, all white
guys from Ivy League schools for the
most part. And uh, now it's different.
>> It was exciting.
>> Oh, I bet it was the I bet it was one of
the most exciting things. I I I used to
park my car out in the north 40
>> and then take like 20 minutes to walk
all the way around the compound so I
could walk in the main door across the
giant seal and see the wall of honor and
the flags and
>> I felt like I wanted to cry, you know? I
was so proud to be there. Felt like you
were part of something.
>> I really did.
>> I can imagine how you feel like you're
part of something. Like what did you
feel like you were part of?
>> Well, you know, I I came from this very
liberal household and I remember my mom
and dad getting into an argument one
time. It was the Pennsylvania primary of
1976.
And my my mom voted my dad voted for
Frank Church who had created the Church
Committee that completely reorganized
the CIA and stripped it of its his power
to its power to, you know, carry out
assassinations and things like that. And
my mom uh voted for Bir who was a
senator from Indiana. And my dad said,
"Burge B, why'd you vote for him?" And
she said, "He's so good-looking." M
>> and my dad's like, "What?
Church is the guy doing all the work."
And I remember being fascinated by this
argument that they were having. So when
when Dr. Post approached me, I called a
friend of mine that I was in class with
who was married to a a guy at the CIA
and I said, "Listen, I'm not a n. I I
know the CIA's history. It's pretty
ugly. Do I want to be involved in an
organization like this? I want to go
into public service. I want to see the
world. She said, "Let's have dinner." So
the three of us get together for dinner
and he's like, "The the bad old days
CIA's of the CIA are gone." The bad old
days, he said, "Yeah, the bad old days
of the CIA are gone." He said, um 75
with the Church Committee in the Senate,
the Pike Committee in the House changed
everything. No more assassinations, no
more overthrowing governments, which was
true for a little while.
>> A little while. Because four years
later, Ronald Reagan becomes president
and next thing you know, we're, you
know, doing Iran Contra and we're
bombing different countries and
everything just went back to the way it
was.
>> But there was like this golden period.
My friends are going to yell at me for
saying that. There was this period where
the CIA was a really awesome place to
work. Got it. And so when you're walking
into that, when you're taking me back to
that moment where you're walking in, did
you feel like I'm a part of something
that's important to America or I'm I'm a
part of just an intriguing life and this
is exciting? Did you feel like I'm like
Clark Kent? Like and and there's no
wrong answer. This is all just like
curiosity.
>> Oh, sure. The first seven and a half
years that I was there, I was an analyst
in actually in the the office that Dr.
Post had founded, the political
psychology division. And um I really
felt like I was a part of something big.
You know, I was only on the job 8 months
and um it was just as I started to feel
like I really knew what I was doing. I
was the I was the leadership analyst,
the psychological analyst on Iraq. And
the reason I was given Iraq was because
not my words. These were the words of my
leadership. Nothing ever happens there.
It's the same cabinet since the 1968
revolution. Nothing ever happens. So,
learn the writing style, learn the
tradecraft, and you can move on to
something interesting like Romania, they
told me.
>> I said, "Great." So, I'm
>> My friend just played ball in Romania,
actually.
>> It's a great place, Romania. I love it.
Oh, yeah. It's great.
>> I got to get over there. I don't know.
My buddy Patrick McCaffrey just he just
finished playing ball over there.
Anyway, carry on.
>> I love it. So, um, just as I get to the
point where I I where I really feel like
I know what I'm doing, Iraq invades
Kuwait, August the 2nd, 1990, I walk
into the office early, like before 7,
and my boss says, "Yeah,
>> shit's popping now. You got to show up."
>> Yeah. I couldn't wait to get into the
office that day. My boss says, "Don't
take your jacket off. We're going to go
to the White House." I had never been in
the White House before.
>> Mhm.
>> And so, um, we go to the White House.
There's this marine standing there. He
walks us into the into the west wing and
we go into the anti- room of the Oval
Office and then the secretary takes us
in and here's the president, the vice
president, the national security adviser
and the CIA director. And so you just
kind of stand there. You wait to be told
what to do. There are two nice chairs
like this. The the president's in that
one, the vice president's in this one.
There's a couch here. My boss and I sat
on on that. There are two like more
uncomfortable chairs over here for the
CI director and the national security
adviser [snorts] and we sit down and the
president goes, "Well, now what do we
do?" And then everybody turns and looks
at me and I'm looking at them and then
it took me a second and I'm like, "Oh,
what? Well, as you know, Mr. president
and Iraqi troops crossed the border at
4:00 this morning and the Kuwaiti roy
royal family ruling family fled to Saudi
Arabia blah blah blah blah but I
remember thinking my friends would never
believe in a million years what I was
doing right now they would never believe
it and I was 20 I was 25 years old and
it happened overnight that you were kind
of suddenly having an influence like you
right there they're like they're looking
to me for information
>> that that actually was kind of a
recurring theme in my career I I was
just very very lucky.
>> Got it.
>> A lot of times.
>> So when you're walking into uh into the
building, when you take that long way
and you pass like the flags and walk
over the seal, it's just like I'm a part
of something.
>> Yeah. You really feel it.
>> Do you think that's the same CIA that we
have today?
>> No. No. 9/11 changed everything and it
changed it permanently
>> in a bunch of different ways. Not just
Have you ever heard of Executive Order
1233?
>> I haven't. 1233 was signed by Gerald
Ford. Um and it it was it came in the
aftermath of the church and pike
committees and um yeah
>> it establish
>> responsibilities and guidelines for the
US uh intelligence uh community.
>> Okay. Executive order 1233 establishes
the goals, responsibilities and
guidelines for the US intelligence
community. Got it.
>> Number one, you can't kill people
anymore. Right. Well, this was after the
Church Commission, right?
>> Exactly. They said you got to stop
killing people. And we had these like,
you know, we we're putting explosives in
Fidel Castro's cigar and putting poison
on the steering wheel of his car and
stupid stuff. And so 1 2 33
>> Tom and Jerry [__]
>> Yeah, exactly. You can't do that stuff
anymore. And then it's been amended over
the years. Well, after 9/11,
Bush is just like, just kill everybody
you want. Wow. And so we set up these
offices,
one whole office called the Special
Activities Division. And then there's in
the counterterrorism center where I was
working, there was one called the the
Special Activities Group. And their job
very simply was just to, you know, send
teams around the world, kill people,
come back, get the list for the next
week, go out there, kill them, come
back, get another list, kill those guys.
It was like uh
nobody was trying to collect
intelligence anymore.
>> Things changed overnight.
>> Overnight.
One time I was um I was traveling
somewhere, you know, cuz I had my
luggage with me and everything and I was
I think I was in Guam maybe or Viet Guam
or somewhere. I don't know.
And I couldn't get the internet. They
didn't have it. They didn't Some people
didn't know what I was talking about.
I'd like point at the sky and then point
at like a book or whatever and they
didn't understand it.
That's where Sally comes in. Sy is an
essential travel tool because it
provides affordable internet data plans
in over 200 destinations giving you
secure internet connection as soon as
you arrive. Yep. Not only that, SLY
saves you money because you're not
getting stung by skyigh roaming charges.
Getting started is really easy. Before
your trip, download the Sally app. Pick
a data plan that suits your trip and
apply my code Theo at checkout to get an
extra 15% off your first purchase. Done.
Say goodbye to surprise roaming charges
and stay protected with SY. That's code
Theo at checkout to get 15% off your
first purchase. You know, my brother
used to bring a little bit of raccoon
over there. A little bit of that
dumpster squirrel, you feel me? He'd
bring it over to uh Thanksgiving over
there and he grill a couple of them up.
Make it make a couple of uh [snorts]
pieces of footwear or something. Couple
hand mittens out of the body fur. Um
that's a power move. That's what we
called it in our family. And when your
mom's friend stayed over just one night,
you know what I'm talking about. That's
power move, guys. Look, we're talking
power moves. I'm talking Morgan and
Morgan. That's a power move. Morgan and
Morgan is America's largest injury law
firm. They have over 100 offices
nationwide and more than 1,000 lawyers.
Morgan and Morgan has a proven track
record of fighting to get you full and
fair compensation. If you're ever
injured, you can check out Morgan and
Morgan. Their fee is free unless they
win. That's the facts. For more
information, go to forthepeople.com/theo
or dial poundlaw. That's pound529 from
your cell phone. That's
fthepeople.com/tho
or poundlaw
pound529.
This is a paid advertisement.
Do you think there's a lot of like
conspiracies about 9/11, right? And I'm
sure you've had um
>> I take a lot of [__] about the
conspiracies. Yeah, you do. I do. I take
a lot of [__] because I don't believe in
them.
>> You don't?
>> No.
>> So, from your experience, cuz you were
there when it happened. You were in the
CIA when it occurred
>> to where we are now. Has your point of
view changed at all since then to now?
>> Yeah. My point of view actually has
changed. So, I don't think I deserve a
lot of the a lot of the sorry, the
criticism that I get. I'm going to start
on July the 6th of 2001.
>> Okay.
>> So,
>> and I'm not familiar with the criticism
either.
>> Okay. I'm glad. I'll explain it to you
then because I I get all the time the
Jews did it. The Saudis did it.
Literally, the space aliens did it. The
Israeli government did it. The Bush
family did it. The, you know, it's like,
come on, people. Nanoothermite paint. I
there's no such thing as nanoothermite
paint that they painted in 1972 to make
the the buildings blow up. Come on, you
guys.
>> That to me sounds very uh that sounds
ridiculous.
>> Yeah, it's ridiculous.
>> Uh but what doesn't sound ridiculous is
somebody having long-term strategy like
you were saying a little while ago that
people play a longer game, right?
>> And we're not good at that generally.
>> Oh yeah, I don't think that we are.
We're we're like a country win
everything now, you know, and we're kind
of a newer country as well. So it's like
and we got everything fast anyway. And
when you get something fast, you don't
really have a ton of respect for it in
some ways.
>> That's right. And it's tough for me to
say that because we all just live like
one lifetime. But I think some of that
could be infectuous over like a society
over time. Um I never even thought about
it before that it's like yeah, when you
get something easy, you're kind of used
to something coming easy. That's it. And
so uh but I do believe that other
countries uh could have strategy against
us. And also,
>> and I believe that there were
>> and what it changed for us as a people,
like what it changed like um for how we
look out of our own eyes, for how we
walk out of like uh
>> I remember on 911 I walked out of a
building. I was staying with some
friends. I walked outside and um there
was just some like construction going on
and it had been going on for a while and
they were like redoing these like uh
this stone walkway. I was in Charleston,
South Carolina, and they had these
bulldozers and stuff out there, and like
people had been excited about the
construction. Like it was like um cuz
the streets there are cobblestone. It's
really beautiful. And suddenly that day
everybody was like, are these like are
they demolishing something? Like
suddenly this had a whole different
energy of like oh like this is the
rubble like there was a connection with
like what you just seen on television to
suddenly like something that was being
done that was positive uh structurally
was now suddenly looked at like there
was a lot of fear around it and I know
that's a ridiculous small thing
>> but that but that's normal that happened
at the time
>> right and it's just it just how much of
a small thing in your head like okay I
just seen this and now everything is
scary that's what I'm trying to say
everything is scary
>> I think that's exactly right the whole
country was traumatized. It It was our
Pearl Harbor, the Pearl Harbor of our
generation.
>> And it change and it changed how you
would operate. It changed um it changed
just like every It It adjusted so many
things. Go on, though.
>> So July 6th, 2001,
um I'm hosting a group of intelligence
officers from a Middle Eastern country.
This is something we did literally every
single day, usually multiple times a
day. And what we do is we set up a day
of briefings. They get a photo op with
the director, you know, shaking hands.
We exchanged gifts and we take them out
to a fancy dinner at night. So these
guys, they were all mid-level like
majors and lieutenant colonels. So it's
a lot of [__]
>> Yeah. A lot of it. A lot. Yes. So I set
up a day of briefings and I I went to
see this kid, young guy, 20s, uh, that
was covering al-Qaeda and I said, "Can
you come and just talk to these guys
about al-Qaeda for an hour?" He said,
"Yes." So it came time for his briefing
but instead of him coming the director
of counterterrorism comes Kofheer Black
>> uh later ambassador Kofer Black and he
comes
>> from which country?
>> Uh the from the US.
>> Yeah. Yeah. He was our director.
Kofheer shows up with the director of
operations from the Osama bin Laden
unit. And um and I jumped up. I was I
was like, "Oh, gentlemen." I said, "This
is this is Kofheer Black. He's the
director of counterterrorism for the
entire American intelligence community.
>> And you were working in counterterrorism
at the time. Got it.
>> And so he came in and and sat down and
he was very very serious. He said, uh,
something terrible is going to happen.
We don't know exactly when or exactly
where, but we know it's going to be an
attack on a scale that we've never seen
before. He said, 'We picking up chatter
from the al-Qaeda training camps where
camp commanders are on the phone with
their students and they're crying and
telling them, "I'll see you in
paradise."
>> We're hearing code words for a massive
attack. The honey salesman is coming
with vast quantities of honey or there's
going to be a huge wedding or a huge
football game. And he said, "We know
that they're planning an enormous
attack. We just don't know when or
where." and he said, "I'm begging you.
If you have any sources inside al-Qaeda,
please help us." They just sat there and
looked at him. Nothing. So, at the end
of the day, I was not working on
al-Qaeda at the time. I later, weeks
later became the chief of uh counter
intelligence in the Osama bin Laden
unit. And so, I went to his office at at
the end of the day before I took those
guys to dinner and I said, "Keofer, I
got to tell you, you shocked me with
that briefing today. Was that just for
them or were you serious? He said, "Oh,
I was deadly serious. Something terrible
is going to happen." And then on
September 11th, there it was. He and I
were supposed to go to the White House
that morning. We had a meeting with
Condisa Rice, who was the National
Security Adviser at the time, on an
issue that's so stupid now, I'm almost
embarrassed to tell you what it is. It
was about a a book that was being
printed by the government printing
office, this minor governmental agency
called Greece, Turkey, Cyprus. No, it
was called Foreign Affairs of the United
States, Greece, Turkey, Cypress, 1949 to
1967. Literally, nobody's going to read
this book.
>> Nobody. I was going to tell you that.
Nobody's gonna read it.
>> Literally nobody.
>> Yeah.
>> And it's like a thousand pages long.
>> That's money laundering.
>> And it had the names of three CIA
sources who were still alive. And we've
got this obscure law in the United
States that if the government outs a CIA
source, we have to offer the source
citizenship. these guys are like 198 and
97 years old. They're not going to they
don't care,
>> right?
>> Nobody's going to read the book anyway.
So, um, we were going to go down there
and ask her, "Just pull those pages out
of the out of the book. You know,
nobody's going to miss it. Nobody's
going to read it anyhow. Just pull the
pages out or redact the names or
whatever."
>> But I went up to tell him that the car
was ready and the secretary's got a
little TV on her desk and the World
Trade Center's on fire. I said, "What
happened to the World Trade Center?" She
said, 'A plane flew into it.' And I go,
because I'm a genius, I said, 'You know,
that happened once before in 1930. A
bomber flew into the Empire State
Building, but it was like pouring rain
and fog. I said, "It's so crystal clear
today. How can you not see that you're
flying into the World Trade Center and
just as I spoke the words, the second
plane hit
>> and then she turned and she said, "Did
you see that or did I imagine it?" And
it's like, oh, everything's going to go
to [__] now. And and at this point,
you're already working in
counterterrorism. Yeah.
>> Well, I was already in counterterrorism,
but I was working on a group. See,
again, I'm embarrassed to even say I was
working in a group that was targeting
European communist terrorists, like
Carlos the Jackal, who nobody remembers
now. He was the Osama bin Laden of the
70s. Nobody remembers who in the world
he was. Really? Yeah. Carlos the Jackal.
>> Bring him up.
>> There he is.
>> Whoa, he looks suave, huh?
>> He was Venezuelan Ilich Ramirez Sanchez.
M
>> listen to the balls this guy had.
OPEC had an oil ministers meeting,
right? So the ministers
>> and for those who don't know what OPEC
is, it's an organization of petroleum
exporting countries. So um it's
basically like your oil kind of
commission.
>> Monopoly. Yeah. Yeah. Monopoly. The uh
what do you call it? The uh cartel. It's
an oil cartel. So he and his gang of
[clears throat] terrorists
raided the OPEC oil ministers meeting in
Vienna, Austria, and kidnapped every
single minister of oil.
>> They killed three people, says there.
>> Oh yeah.
>> He and he demanded a plane, flew
everybody to Libya, took his billion
dollars ransom that they gave him, and
then let everybody go.
>> Wow. So he was just trying to get a bag,
really, huh?
>> Oh, yeah. And he was good at it. And
then he was so good at it, he set up
terrorist training camps in Libya and
Lebanon. And he trained the IRA, the
Irish Republican Army. He trained
Greece's revolutionary organization 17
November, the Red Brigades, the Axion
direct.
>> Why did he feel so convicted to to do
this sort of behavior?
>> He was a true believing communist
>> and he just wanted to bring down the
West.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Interesting.
>> Yeah.
>> But take me back. So it's like you guys
hear that something's going to happen.
>> Something terrible is gonna happen.
>> But what do you do at that point? Well,
see that's the key. What do you do? We
we didn't know what to do. So we're
going to the, you know, Jordanians, the
Egyptians, the Saudis, the this one,
then that one. And they're like, we
don't know what's going on. Well, as it
turned out, that wasn't true. Um,
almost all the hijackers, what was it?
17, 16 or 17 of the hijackers came from
Saudi Arabia, right? And we know that
the Saudi ambassador to the United
States at the time, Prince Bandar bin
Sultan al-Sah, his wife transferred
$50,000 from her personal bank account
to the hijackers.
>> What are we supposed to make of that?
>> Yeah. Sometimes you got to get your girl
to Vimmo if you got it. You know what
I'm saying?
>> Seriously, you know, the only time I
ever saw George Tennant, it was the CIA
director at the time, the only time I
ever saw George completely lose his [__]
was in a meeting with Prince Bandar. He
said, "If we don't start getting help
from the Saudi government
on this case, we're going to start
killing people, a lot of people, and
some of them are going to be named al-
Sud."
I go out to Pakistan as the chief of uh
counterterrorism operations there in
January of O2. So, it's still fresh.
We're bombing Tora Bora, all these
al-Qaeda people trying to get out of
Afghanistan, cross into into Pakistan.
And my job was then to catch them when
they came into
>> We're bombing what? We're bombing We're
bombing which country?
>> Afghanistan.
>> We're bombing Afghanistan, right? But
there was Why were we looking for
al-Qaeda in Afghanistan?
>> That's where they were living. All of
them. They launched 9/11 from
Afghanistan.
>> Got it.
>> At least
theoretically the ideas came when they
were in Afghanistan.
>> Well, because from the American like
population, it always felt like we never
went after Saudi Arabia. That's what it
felt like.
>> Yeah. And we should have. But if you
didn't you know that
>> we did not we suspected but we didn't
have there was no smoking gun. So that's
what I'm getting to. We catch Abu Zuba
Zay Albadin Muhammad Hussein. Abu Zuba
who we believed at the time I thought
you were having a stroke for a second.
>> No it's his name.
>> No I'm just joking. That was a joke.
>> The profession I know the profession of
faith.
>> I've been around people that are
stroking out and if you don't tap in
with them they'll just keep going. Oh
jeez.
>> You know, and then they never buy a
vowel and then they just [__] tap
out, you know.
>> That's terrible.
>> So you guys were doing this guy.
>> So we're looking for him.
>> Oh bro. And we catch him. This dude is a
[__] mumble rapper, I think. Go on.
>> He We were on him for 6 weeks. We chased
him. Some days we'd bust down the door
and there's like a warm meal and a half
lit cigarette still on the table. We're
like, "Dang it, 15 minutes we could have
gotten him."
>> Some days we were a day or two behind.
So he knew we were after him. He knew we
were chased him all over the freaking
country and we catch him in late March
2002 in Fisalabad, Pakistan. So we also
confiscated his diary. This this led to
a huge fight between the FBI and the
CIA. Huge. And the CIA was right and the
FBI was wrong. But um
the the fight was well we had we had
captured his diary. So,
>> dude, that sounds so suspect that he has
a diary.
>> It was more than a diary though.
>> But even though, you know what I'm
saying? Like as a regular person.
>> No, it didn't have terrorism stuff in
it,
>> right? But even then, first of all, who
the [__] has a
>> See, but look,
>> he does have an eye patch.
>> Sketcher. Yeah.
>> Oh, he drew a lot as well.
>> It's It's all drawings. All of it.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Yeah. All of its drawings. And most of
them are classified top secret. The uh
the CIA wouldn't allow them to be
released. Got it. Um because they were
mostly about the torture that was done
to him.
>> Understood.
>> So anyway, we catch the diary and I call
headquarters and I said, "Listen, we got
his diary and there's some fascinating
[__] in here." Like what? And I said,
"Well, for one, there are the cell phone
numbers of three Saudi princes. Like
what's up with that?" So they were like,
"Put it in writing." So I write this
cable back and I was like, "We found
these three princes. Here are their cell
phone numbers. George calls in the Saudi
ambassador. The president calls the
king, "What kind of country you running
over there?"
So we said, "We want those three
princes. We want them like right now."
Next thing you know, one goes into the
hospital for beriatric surgery cuz
they're all fat.
>> Mhm.
>> And he dies on the operating table.
>> The other one is driving from Riyad to
Jedha on the Riyad Jedha Highway. He's
in a onecar accident and is killed in
the accident. The third one goes camping
in the desert, which is a very popular
pastime, and dies of thirst.
>> Yeah. So, we couldn't interrogate any of
them.
>> Who do you think was Do you think that
uh Saudi Arabia did that?
>> 100%.
>> Right. Do you think we ever got uh to
the bottom of 911? Do you think you
don't?
>> No. And I'm going to say something
that's very unpopular. Um, I think that
the Israelis, while not involved in 911,
absolutely, positively had advanced
warning of 911. They had sources inside
of al-Qaeda and they purposely did not
tell us the details because they knew
what was going to happen. They knew that
we would attack Afghanistan and we would
attack Iraq and we would kill 2 million
Muslims. And I mean, these dancing
Israelis, they've never answered for
this. I'm still mad about the dancing
Israelis.
>> I've heard about the dancing Israelis.
Bring it up.
>> So, you're saying that you believe that
they knew?
>> I think they knew in advance and didn't
warn us.
>> But they didn't warn us because we would
then we would
>> we would do their dirty work for them.
>> We would take out issues with their
surrounding guys. You know, there are
videos making the rounds now of Benjamin
Netanyahu over the years, over the the
last 20 plus years, testifying before
Congress and saying, you know, if if we
just took out Saddam Hussein, we would
be peace in the Middle East. If we just
took out Muamar Gaddafi, there would be
I guarantee you, he says, there would be
peace in the Middle East. And we do it
all.
>> We to take out Iran and we're going to
have peace in the Middle East.
>> It's starting to get a little bit more
like I think so. A little sus.
>> Yeah. So, um, the Iraqis have electrical
towers like we have everywhere, but ours
have four legs and the Iraqis have three
legs. So, just a few days before we
attacked Iraq, at that time, I'm the I'm
the executive assistant to the deputy
director for operations at the CIA. So,
it's a serious the most serious job I
ever had in my life.
>> So, you have access to a lot.
>> Literally everything.
>> Wow.
>> And the Israelis come to us and they
said, "Listen, you guys are going to
attack Iraq in a couple days." We want
in. We said absolutely not. We put this
coalition together with all these Arab
countries. As soon as you guys jump in,
all the Arabs are going to drop out.
Just let us do it. Next thing you know,
every one of these electrical towers
just begins to topple over like 150
miles worth in the Western Desert
because somebody put explosives on just
one of the three legs.
>> And I remember my boss saying, "These
damn Israelis, they just can't leave
well enough alone.
They just don't ever do as they're told.
>> Um, let me look at this. The dancing
Israelis, and we're talking about the
Israeli government. We're not talking
about Israeli people.
>> I'm I'm far less worried about the
dancing Israelis than than I am about
the Israelis who were arrested on 911.
>> Okay.
>> But just so I just so I can say the
claim because I don't know, I've never
even spoken about this. The dancing
Israelis is a 911 related conspiracy
trope based on the arrest of five
Israeli men in New Jersey on September
11, 2001. Um, and this is uh according
to Perplexity, and it was some guys, I
think they were on a building top and
they were kind of dancing like around a
highing each other.
>> Yeah. A bread truck or something as the
uh as you can see the towers in the
distance. Um, yeah, a New Jersey woman
reported five men near a van overlooking
Manhattan who appeared to be celebrating
and taking photos as the Twin Towers
burned. Police later stopped a
suspicious van and detained five Israeli
citizens. Um they had items like box
cutters and multiple passports which
conspiracy theorists later fixated on
but box cutters are normal tools for a
moving delivery job. Um they were happy
because they knew exactly what was going
to happen that we would have to enter
the war. We would attack Afghanistan. We
would probably then you know uh take a
permanent position in the in the region
which is exactly what happened. That's
why they were dancing. They were happy
911 is a good thing for Israel. Yeah,
>> it got us militarily engaged over the
long term.
>> But you don't think that they were
involved in the setting up of it?
>> I don't. No, no, no. There's And there's
never been any evidence to suggest that
they were involved in any way.
>> I have no idea.
>> No. But there was another thing, too,
and this is this is a bigger issue. Um,
it's that
uh the Israelis spy on the United
States. They've always spied on the
United States.
>> Do we spy on them also?
>> No. And and that's written in stone at
the CIA. We do not spy on Israel, but
they openly spy on us. They're all over
the country stealing defense secrets.
>> Do we spy on other countries?
>> Yeah, we spy on almost every
>> Why can't we spy on them?
>> It's a political decision that's been
made.
>> Yeah. A political decision in the White
House, on Capitol Hill.
>> Sometimes it just feels like our country
is just kind of owned by Israel and they
just don't say that. Do you think that
that's true or do you think that's
fictional?
>> Well, I don't think it's so clear-cut. I
think I think the truth is that the
Israelis have inordinate political
influence in the United States,
especially in our elections.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, they just had that election with
Thomas Massie that um
>> Exactly. That That's the best example
>> that got overtaken. What happened with
that election? Let's bring it up. I
mean, I know that Thomas lost, but it
was it was the largest.
>> Yeah. $35 million was spent. The
American Israel Public Affairs Committee
or Apac and other [snorts] pro-Israel
interest groups have unccorked over 9
million in a bid to unseat Republican
Representative Thomas Massie on Tuesday,
which they did in a competitive primary
that has shattered spending records. Uh
prominent pro-Israel GOP donors have
funneled millions more into a super PAC
stood up by President Donald Trump's
political operation that has spent
nearly 7 million on the race. Overall ad
spending has topped 32 million, making
it the most expensive House primary on
record per tracking firm ad impact. Wow.
>> For a job that pays $180,000 a year.
>> So, what are the long-term benefits of
them getting this position? Or was it
just about getting Massie out?
>> It was getting Massie. The thing about
Apac is if you are not 100% pro-Israel,
they will primary you. They'll they'll
primary you with somebody who is 100%
pro-Israel. And sometimes,
you know, the perfect is the enemy of
the good. Where um what does that mean?
>> Uh where you've got, for example, there
was an incumbent Democrat in New Jersey
who voted pro-Israel 90% of the time.
They ran a primary opponent against him.
Um and uh who was 100% pro-Israel and he
lost, but so did she. And the one that
won was the one that's pro Palestinian.
>> Ah, I see. So sometimes by taking out by
by aiming for one, you might let another
through.
>> You end up hurting your own cause.
>> Got it. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well, I think I mean I can
understand people's uh angst with this
sort of thing. I mean the the biggest
thing is just like if Israel is involved
in a genocide, right? They're genociding
people. It's almost like why would you
let Nazi Germany invest in your in your
people who are going to be running
congressmen or senators in your country?
It's crazy. I don't see how there's not
a law. Like, why isn't there a law if
there's some if a country's doing like a
like a holocaust or like a genocide that
they're not allowed to invest in um that
they're not allowed to have a lobby in
in in our elections? See, was there ever
a law about that?
>> No. And and they would lose their [__]
over the use of the word genocide. You
used it. I use it. It's a genocide. It
meets
>> We've been using it on here for years.
>> Oh, yeah. It meets all the international
legal requirements of a genocide.
>> Yeah. Well, I think the UN is has voted
that it is. Yeah. Um I don't know if the
vote passed because I think there was
maybe some groups that were that
wouldn't agree to it. Um
>> Well, it didn't pass the Security
Council, but it passed by 90 something%
in the general assembly. Yeah, but I
just I don't understand why that seems
fair. And also, I'm amazed that I don't
understand why people that made like
movies and wrote books about the
Holocaust, why they don't speak up and
say, "Hey,
>> yeah, this is the same thing that I
wrote about." You know what I'm saying?
You can show picture to picture that
makes it exactly
>> killing is wrong.
>> It's wrong. No matter who's doing the
killing or who's being killed, it's just
wrong.
>> But I don't see why some of those people
don't speak up,
>> you know.
>> Well, there there is an increasingly
large number of Jewish Americans who are
speaking out. There's a big group called
Jewish Voices for Peace. Um the Orthodox
Jewish community in New York has been
very vocal just this week. Uh there was
um protest annual Israel Day parade and
>> and a lot of the Orthodox Jews from
Brooklyn showed up with Palestinian and
Iranian flags and it caused violence.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I guess I just don't understand
why
what are like what is America afraid of
like like what have you seen like in the
CIA because it does you hear a lot that
like that that the Israeli influence
>> like has taken over our CIA and our FBI.
Do you think that that's true or not?
>> Well, I can't speak to the FBI and my my
CIA information is dated. I left the CIA
more than 20 years ago, but when I was
there, we kept the Israelis at arms
length. like seriously. So, um the very
first intelligence liaison intelligence
briefing I ever gave was to the
Israelis. I had been only on the job six
weeks and my boss said, "Listen, you're
going to give a liazison briefing. It's
going to be a whole big group of people.
So, you're going to be the last one to
talk because you're the most junior, but
you need to know some of the ground
rules." He said, "We do not meet with
the Israelis in the building. We used
to, but every time they'd come, they'd
bring us gifts. And the gifts are always
packed with listening devices and
batteries.
>> Is that true?
>> Yes. 100% true.
>> Would you guys find them? How do you
even know that that's true?
>> Because you have to x-ray everything
that comes into the building. You can't
just wantingly walk in off the street
with, you know, boxes of gifts and say,
"Here, this is for you."
>> And what they do to sew a couple
Palestinian ears from the rubble
>> and they're like, [laughter]
"Oh, we're just joking."
>> Oh, it's like joking stuff.
>> Yeah, it's not joking.
>> Right. So, that happened during your
time. Was that with other countries too?
So I'm sure there's other countries that
like
>> Oh, there are other countries we don't
even have liaison with.
>> Got it.
>> But with the Israelis, we had to we had
to rent a place and we would meet with
them in the place. Um on my very first
day at the CIA, you you meet in the
auditorium called the bubble and the
head of HR comes out and the director
comes and says, "Welcome to the CIA."
And then the head of security, it's just
a parade of important people come to
welcome you. So the head of security
said, he said a couple things. One was
funny. He said, "The gravest threat
facing America today is the threat of
Soviet communism." And I said to the guy
next to me, "Does this guy not read the
papers? There is no Soviet Union
anymore." Anyway, he went on to say that
the Israelis have two declared
intelligence officers in the United
States, one Mossad and one Shinbet. So
CIA and FBI equivalents. They're at the
Israeli embassy in Washington. But the
FBI has identified
187 additional undeclared Israeli
intelligence officers spread out all
over America
>> stealing secrets from defense
contractors.
So the the lesson was don't ever talk
about work outside the building. Don't
ever eat at the restaurants in MLAN,
Virginia, because they're all Russian
KGB and back then it was the KGB and
Israeli Mossad agents eating there to
hear what the CIA people are saying
afterward.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah,
>> it sounds exciting though. At least
>> it was kind of exciting.
>> I bet it was. It was like a real who
done it.
>> I I loved it. I really did. I loved it
until I didn't love it. You know,
>> in after 911, everybody went nuts and
just wanted to kill everyone. I was
getting ready to go to Pakistan and so I
stopped by the office on my way to the
airport just to say goodbye because
Kofheer said on 911 he stood up on his
desk.
>> Kofer Black, you said
>> Kofheer Black. Yeah. He stood up on his
desk and he said, "Today we're at war.
All of us are going to have to do our
part. Not all of us are going to be able
to come home."
>> So he said, "If you if you want to walk
now, walk and nobody will think less of
you." Nobody budged. So I stopped by the
office cuz I wanted to say goodbye. I
don't know. Am I going to get shot? Am I
going to get blown up? Am I going to get
killed? I I don't know. So, I just want
to say goodbye.
>> Say goodbye to Kofheer.
>> No. To Kofheer. To my boss, excuse me,
[clears throat] and to the people I was
working with.
>> Well, why would you have gotten shot?
I'm
>> I was the chief of counterterrorism
operations. That's the job I'm going out
to. I'm busting down doors three nights
a week. And um and I worked for this
guy. Lovely, lovely guy. Nice suits,
just a really like like very
professorial.
And he gives me a hug and he leans in
and he says, "Kill them all." And I
said, "Really? Have we gotten there
already?" Wow.
>> And he says, "Kill them all." And then I
went to the airport. I was like, "Am I
the only guy who thinks we should do
this by the book?" God.
>> Apparently I was.
That's crazy, man. It was ugly. You
should see some of the pictures I have
on my phone. Those make your hair stand
up.
>> I don't know. I'm already There's
already a lot of stuff I'm not allowed
to look at.
>> [laughter]
>> Um, I have blockers on my phone. So, uh,
yeah, I'm just gonna donate my eyes to
charity, I think, soon. Um, this episode
is sponsored by BetterHelp.
For some, summer is their favorite
season. Travel picks up and the kids are
out of school and adventure is the
focus.
For others, juggling it all can be tough
and and they're just counting down the
minutes until the kids are back in
school. If you're feeling off, this is a
reminder to check in with yourself. Hey
self, what's going on? BetterHelp can
help. With over 30,000 therapists,
BetterHelp is the world's largest online
therapy platform, having served over 6
million people globally. And it works.
With an average rating of 4.9 out of
five for a live session based on over
1.7 million client reviews, you don't
have to say yes to everything this
summer. Find support in therapy. Sign up
and get 10% off at betterhelp.com/theo.
That's betterhp.com/to.
I've been wondering if there was ever a
time when you were with your family and
your car broke down because I've been
there and I remember my the car was
broke down and I stood off. I walked off
from that thing. I said, "I ain't even
being with y'all anymore. Just just
didn't even want to be by my family.
Dang it." Just out of shame. Car Shield
could have fixed that. Car Shield offers
month-to-month vehicle protection plans
designed to protect drivers from
expensive car repair bills.
Car Shield contracts have low
deductibles to prevent stress to your
wallet at a critical time, and they
partner with certified mechanics and
repair shops around the country for when
you're in a bind. Make a decision your
wallet will love with Car Shield. Right
now, CarShield is offering our listeners
20% off with the code theo at
carshield.com.
Visit carshield.com to lock in your 2026
protection today and protect yourself
from expensive car repairs. Again, go to
carshield.com and use code theo for 20%
off.
So when you get involved like how bad
did it get after 911 where the rules of
like um interrogating and that sort of
thing changed?
>> Ah that's a good question. You know the
the dirty little secret was
literally not one single CIA officer was
trained in interrogation techniques.
Wow. So I as soon as we started catching
these guys, I mean I had only been there
but a week we started catching them and
my boss is like interrogate them. I'm
like I'm I don't know how to interrogate
people. I can interview them. And what
do you even wear sneakers? What do you
even put on to do? Something like that.
>> Yeah, I wore sneakers most days. Uh polo
shirt, jeans.
>> Bro, you can't interrogate somebody in a
polo shirt.
>> That's all I brought with me. That and
sweatshirts cuz it was cold when I
arrived.
>> You got to put on a Chicago Bears jersey
or something. Oh my god, it was so
weird. See, in one of the early raids,
we had also confiscated the al-Qaeda
training manual.
>> Well, I I
>> Do you still have one of those or not?
You think?
>> No, no, no. I turned everything in.
>> Uh, but you know what? It might be
online.
>> It might be out there now.
>> I one.
>> So, I was uh I spoke and and read Arabic
and so we're going through the training
manual and I and I'm translating it to
the guys at my branch as I'm reading it.
Well, everything that was in the manual,
these prisoners would do as we would
catch them. So, I say, "What's your
name?" The guy goes, "Oh, like he's
having a ruptured appendix." Oh, what's
your name? And he like pretends to faint
and falls off the chair and then he just
kind of opens one eye to look at you.
I'm like, "Get the [__] up and get back
in the chair. What's your name?" And
then like, "Do you do you hit him? Do
you not hit him? Do you grab him by the
shirt and shake?" I mean, I didn't know
what the rules were.
>> There were no rules. And so what kind of
environ I mean what did you end up
having to do? Like what do you do in
those sort of situations? Like are you
responsible to garner information? Do
you even feel like the people you're
catching have real information? The [__]
sounds kind of vague.
Everybody has something. It's called the
mosaic concept where everybody's got a
little tile in his brain and if you
collect enough tiles you can put the
whole picture together. So I mean some
of it sounds comical now. Um,
I would say to the Pakistani lieutenant
colonel that I was working with on a
daily basis, I'd say, "You want to be
the good cop today? I'll be the bad cop
or you want to be the the bad cop again?
I'll be the good cop." And then we
decide in advance. Then I go in, you
know, we start talking to these guys.
The first guy we captured, he was
Jordanian. And they bring him in, he's
shackled at the ankles, shackled at the
waist, and then they undo the waist
shackle, and they they chain him to an
eyebolt in the in the table.
So, you have to know the answers to all
the questions that you're asking, right?
So, I'm like, what's your name? He tells
me his name. Uh, how where did you come
from? I came from Tora Bora. And what
happened in Tora Bora? The Americans
began bombing us. And then, where did
you go? He said, I tried to escape. So,
I went into a cave and then the
Americans bombed the cave and the guy
like had blood squirted out of his ears
and he had brain damage and finally made
it across the border. I lay out a map.
Tell me exactly how you got across the
border. We knew what the rat lines were.
And he told the truth. This is the way
we came through this pass.
Everything he told me was true. And so I
I said to him, he said, "What's going to
happen to me?" And I said, "Honestly, I
don't know. You're probably going to
spend some time in jail here and then
we're going to send you to Jordan, and I
don't know what the Jordanians are going
to do to you." Because he was Jordanian.
Yeah. So I said to him, "But let me ask
you something.
I know that what you told me was true.
Why did you tell me the truth? And he
goes, I'm your prisoner. What good would
it do me to lie to you? He said, I know
how these things work. I know that you
knew the answers to these questions. It
doesn't help me in any way to lie to
you.
>> And then I said, okay, thank you. And
then he says, let me ask you something
now. He said, I assume you're Christian.
And I said, yes. And he says, "I would
like to invite you into the embrace of
Islam and I'll be your godfather."
I said, "Well, thank you very much."
>> And what is that? It's almost like the
boy scouts or something or he like as a
scout leader kind of like like he'll
like be like your sponsor.
>> Yeah. Like my sponsor. He's going to
convert me to Islam and I'm going to
say,
>> which is Muslim. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And um and uh I said, "Yeah,
thanks, but no thanks. And I wish you
the best." And I remember saying to a
colleague of mine, "My god, if everyone
goes like that, it's going to be
incredible." The next raid we did,
we bust down the door 2:00 in the
morning and it's two kids. They're 19
years old from Tunisia and they both
just burst into tears. Oh.
>> And so we cuff them and one kid is just
heaving, sobbing, and the other one is
begging me to let him call his mother.
And I'm like, "No, I'm sorry. You can't
call your mother." what they do. They
they were Arabs without passports or
visas in an al-Qaeda safe house. And
that was good enough for me.
>> Got it. So, we got to the point where we
had literally filled the Rahul Pindi
jail in in Rahul Pindi, Pakistan. It's
it's this gigantic city that's kind of
attached to Islamabad. Islamabad is the
capital, but it's very, very small. Mhm.
>> Raul Pindi is where the military is
located and it's like five, six, seven
million people there. So, uh,
Raul Pendi jail. There it is. That's it.
My god, I haven't
>> I haven't been to the Ra Pendy jail in
24 years.
>> I tell you what, I don't remember it
looking that good either.
>> I never been.
>> Well, yeah. Thank your lucky stars.
>> Really?
>> Yeah. It's not good. So So
the the PS called me and they said,
"Look, we've we've literally filled the
jail. you got to do something with these
guys. I said, "Okay." So, I call
headquarters. I said, "The packs are
telling me that the jail's full. What do
you want to do with them?" They said,
"Put them on a C12 and send them to
Guantanamo." I said, "Guantamo? Cuba?
Why would we send them to Cuba?" And
they said, "We came up with this idea.
We're going to send everybody to Cuba
and then we're going to divide them up
after we figure out what federal
district court to charge them with."
Because 911 was an open criminal
investigation at the time and the crimes
were committed in the Eastern District
of Massachusetts hijacking the Western
District of Pennsylvania hijacking the
Eastern District of Virginia, the
Pentagon, and the Southern District of
New York.
>> I said, "That's a great idea." So, we
just started loading these guys on an
endless, you know, parade of C12
transport planes and sending them to
Guantanamo. And then somebody in Dick
Cheny's office, probably David
Addington, although he's never admitted
it, somebody said, "You know what? These
guys don't have any rights in Cuba. Why
don't we just leave them there like
forever?"
>> And here we are 24 years later.
>> Some of them are still there.
>> And they're still there.
>> Most of them, you think?
>> 34 of them. At the height we had like
770 I think was when it was at its most
full.
>> I went there one time as a to perform as
a comedian. Yeah.
>> Went down there and was performing for
some of the troops there and stuff. You
got to see some of the uh just the way
you would fly in it.
>> See it in the distance.
>> Oh yeah. When you the way you'd fly in
at night uh they would fly in like this
kind of crazy pattern and um
>> Yeah, they do.
>> And it was lit up. It almost looked like
a big wedding ring in the distance
because they had like just these bright
bright lights. um on the fences
surrounding the uh the base. And so you
come in like at this crazy kind of
pattern and uh and you kind of had to go
around. We went from I think
>> you can't cross Cuban airspace. You have
to go around and come up from the south.
>> We went from somewhere in Florida and
went around. It was pretty intense. I
mean, it was definitely it was
interesting. Uh, and then we got to go
right up by the by the detainee centers
and I think we even saw some guys
playing volleyball and stuff, but um,
were there tortures where people lost
their lives? Were you that you were
involved in?
>> Not that I was involved in, thank God.
There were, you know,
>> but like at what point do you call like
one office getting out of hand? Like
have you been in one that was getting
out of hand?
>> No, because when we were catching guys,
we had not yet implemented the torture
program. So the torture program was was
conceived and approved in October of
2001.
>> Okay.
>> I got to Pakistan in January of 2002
and we're like what do we do with these
guys? We the FBI's there with us there.
You can't you can't like hit them or you
can't do anything to them. If they don't
talk then okay we just send them to
Guantanamo.
>> And because you you ended up coming out
and talking speaking out about uh
torture that was happening,
>> right? But how would they let you do
that if you weren't aware of it
firsthand though?
>> Well, because remember I became the
executive assistant to the deputy
director.
>> Oh, so you would see the reports coming
back. You see all the cables coming back
in?
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> Huh.
>> Mhm.
>> Was some of it pretty intense. Do you
feel like
>> Oh, it was bad. You know, I most most of
the news outlets that I talked to, they
make the biggest deal out of water
boarding. There's water boarding right
there.
>> Um I think that there were there were
techniques that were worse than
waterboarding. Sleep deprivation
>> Yeah. is one. Um, and in terms of
causing death, uh, the cold cell, you
see, sensory deprivation, that was also
a terrible one.
>> What is that like?
>> Sensory deprivation, they put you in in
like an isolation tank.
>> Mhm.
>> And you're surrounded by water and you
literally go crazy from the silence.
So, you're in like a like one of those
uh like kind of one of those places you
can go pay to do and it's like quiet in
there.
>> But instead of being in there for an
hour or two hours, you're in there for 3
weeks.
>> Is there are they playing music or
>> No, it's it's complete silence and
darkness. Complete and total like you're
dead.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> I think Aaron Rogers does that.
>> Yeah. I think that's nuts. But there
were a couple that were worse than than
uh waterboarding. The cold cell. We
strip the prisoner naked. You chain him
to an eyebolt in the ceiling so he can't
lay or sit or get comfortable in
>> you. You keep your underpants on or you
>> No, no, no, no. Because the idea is to
humiliate them.
>> Remember in their religion?
>> Oh.
>> Uh nakedness is shameful.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Nakedness in front of a woman.
And we would have women interrogators
stripped them naked just to humiliate
them.
>> Yeah. You see this rectal feeding? Um
>> rectal feeding.
>> Yeah. What we did is we forced tubes up
their asses and then with a pump pumped
hummus up there
>> just to insult their culture.
>> No way.
>> Who was coming up with these ideas? I'm
sure
>> there were two contract psychologists at
the CIA. Um James Mitchell and Bruce
Jessen.
>> Is that true?
>> They came up with these plans.
>> Yeah. And we paid them $108 million of
the taxpayers money for it.
>> Wow. But when you look at were these
people criminals? I see. This is what's
in
>> That's the thing. That's the thing,
Theo. They've never been charged with a
crime,
>> right?
>> So, charge them. If these guys are as
bad as we say they are, charge them with
a crime. If they're as bad as we say
they are, find them guilty, sentence
them to death, and execute them. We
won't even charge people in our country
who are committing a crime. A crime.
>> No.
>> So, I think that it's like
that's like a problem that's been across
the board is like what is the crime?
Charge somebody with a crime.
>> Yeah. It's not happening in our own
country because this is so wild to hear
about because it's like
>> you know it's really it's interesting
like just as a person right you're like
okay did these guys do something really
bad to kill people in our country right
did were they doing really harmful stuff
or they like
>> and they were
>> right
>> yeah but they confessed through torture
so none of it's admissible none of it
>> right okay so but then it's like yeah
it's like how do you solve something
like that you know with war crime. Well,
there was a there was a deal that was
made during the Biden administration.
So, it was it was like the top three or
four um Khalik Muhammad uh Amar Al
Baluch Ramsey binib and somebody else.
Um, they agreed to plead guilty to
terrorism
and what they got in exchange was life
without parole
and a promise not to send them to
supermax in Colorado because they they
said they couldn't deal with the cold.
They wanted to stay in Cuba because it's
warm.
>> So, life without parole. And Biden's uh
secretary of defense um vacated the deal
and he says, "You can't make a deal like
that. I have to make that deal because
I'm the Secretary of Defense. And it
went through the courts. And then the
Biden administration, there it is right
there.
>> The Biden administration, Department of
Defense. Um, and who were these four
guys? They were the men accused
>> Muhammad, Wally Bin Tash, Mustafa Hawi.
>> They were accused of plotting the
September 11 terrorist attacks, right?
The Biden administration, Department of
Defense reached plea agreements with uh
three prominent al-Qaeda figures whom
you just mentioned, accused of plotting
the September 11th terrorist attacks.
However, following intense political and
public backlash, the administration
moved to block the agreement and the
courts later threw it out. So, what
happened to the guys? They're just still
in being still there. You see right
there the terms they they agreed to
plead guilty to murdering 2,976
people
>> in exchange for life without parole.
>> Okay. So, the deal was thrown out. So,
now what do they have?
>> They have life without parole. They
That's the deal,
>> right? Same thing.
>> It's the same thing. They're never going
to be released.
>> But why didn't we What was the reason
why there? Oh, because the reaction from
people.
>> It was It was really reaction from the
Biden administr.
I guess they
>> Well, the 911 families just want to chop
everybody's head off. And I understand.
I get it. I really do.
>> It makes sense. I get it. But that's
never going to happen. It's never going
to happen. We're a country of laws. We
can't just pretend that we're a country
of laws except when the laws aren't
convenient for us.
>> But if you kill enough people, it seems
like you would face the death penalty.
>> Yes. But this you have the you have to
blame the CIA for that. If the CIA
hadn't tortured these guys, they would
all be have inadmissible.
>> It's all inadmissible. Got it. They
confessed everything, but it was all
under torture.
>> And so you can't do anything with it.
Now, there's no evidence against them.
None.
>> What a I can't even imagine what it's
like to be some of those families and
like and just the drawn out of all of
that.
>> It's been 24 year 25 years in in
September.
>> Um, let's get a little bit more current.
Did you Oh, did you see that they just
had the like they have those flatillas
that are going to Gaza? Did you see that
the prime minister of Ireland's sister
was on one of them?
>> [laughter]
>> I'll tell you, the Irish hate the
Israelis and the Israelis hate the
Irish. Has that always been the case,
you think?
>> No, only in the last eight or 10 years.
Let me see this. Gaza aid flotillaa
activist home after torture ship
nightmare. Scroll a little. Uh, Irish
activists have claimed they were
kidnapped and beaten by Israeli forces
after their aid flotilla to Gaza was
intercepted in international waters.
Margaret Connelly, the sister of
President Connelly, was among the
emotional arrivals at Dublin airport on
Saturday. They wanted us to suffer, she
said. None of them could look us in the
eye. What a dehumanizing thing to do to
men and women aged from 22 to 75. That's
just wild. Imagine if like Obama's
sister or
>> Can you imagine?
>> Can't even imagine. I want to interview
Greta Thurberg.
>> Oh, that would be fun.
>> It'd be cool, huh?
>> Yeah.
>> I just would like to get to see what
she's like.
>> You know, I never been around her. I
just see you just see like bits and
clips of people, right?
>> Um, so it'd be pretty fascinating. The
Irish detainees were among hundreds of
part participants from other countries
who were also detained when the latest
iteration of the global sum sim flotilla
flotillaa was stopped by Israeli forces
in international waters and a lot of
these groups were trying to get there to
bring aid to the people in Gaza and then
also I think to just document what was
going on there. Um, they've had the
largest killing of journalists.
>> Yeah.
>> In the history of time.
>> Yeah. Of the world.
>> In the history of the world.
>> Yeah. How are people not outraged? Have
you heard of um
>> I don't know if people have any feelings
anymore. I don't know what's going on.
>> Have you heard of Shireen Abu Akla?
>> No. I couldn't even hear that. I don't
even know how to, you know, [laughter] I
couldn't I couldn't do it if I Yeah.
Shireen Abu Akla was an American citizen
and she was the top journalist on Al
Jazzer. So um bring her up Shireen
>> Shireen Abu Akla.
>> Abu Akla.
>> So again, American citizen. She goes to
Israel and she's covering the uh the
fighting between the Israelis and
Palestinians. I think it was in the in
the West Bank. There she is.
>> Yeah, in the West Bank. So, she's
wearing a bulletproof vest that says
press and she's wearing a helmet that
says press and she's she's taking cover
behind a tree and an Israeli sniper shot
her in the face
>> and killed her. Killed her instantly.
So, her funeral is held a couple days
later in a Greek Orthodox church in the
West Bank. The IDF raids the church,
beats the pawbearers, and they drop the
the coffin.
>> You're lying.
>> Isn't that awful? Let me see. The manner
of her death and the subsequent vi
violent disruption of her funeral drew
widespread international condemnation of
Israel. During her funeral procession,
the Israel police attacked the pawbears
at the St. Joseph's Hospital in East
Jerusalem with batons and stun grenades.
The hospital itself was also stormed by
Israeli police officers who assaulted
patients and threw stun grenades. What
is
>> an American citizen?
>> Unbelievable.
>> We and we didn't say anything.
>> We didn't say anything.
Well, most of our media won't say a lot
of stuff about this.
>> No.
>> What do you think's going on? It feels
like this is almost like
>> it almost feels like um like the
Twilight Zone.
>> Does that make any sense to you?
>> Yes, very much.
>> Well, as someone who's seen like a lot
of like SCOPs and things that go on,
what's going on here? Like like does
Israel have like an end goal? Like I
like I have a lot of Jewish friends that
are great people and stuff like that,
right? And one of my best friends is an
IDF special forces veteran.
>> No way.
>> Yeah. How does he feel about this sort
of
>> He's ashamed. He's ashamed. He's like,
"We didn't used to be like this."
>> I just don't under like Is there some
goal of Israel? That's is a bigger goal.
Do you think? Do you think so?
>> Well, the goal might be in the 2027
National Defense Authorization Act, it
integrates for the first time ever the
Israeli and American militaries. So they
become like one military. It's like who
who thought of that? Oh, my friend Roana
actually is putting together
>> Wow.
>> He's trying to put together a bill, I
think, to challenge this. I'm not and I
don't know if the term is a bill. I'm
not sure. So, you know, I'm more of an
emotional guy than I am.
>> I like and respect Roana. I hope he runs
for president.
>> He's a neat guy. We had him on here and
it was it was cool. I think he's a I
think he's a really interesting guy. I
think he's brave. Um I like the stuff
that he's brave enough to do. Um see,
and I say the same thing about Tucker
Carlson.
>> I think I think Tucker the I'll tell you
something about Tucker is the Tucker
that you see on the screen, that's
Tucker in real life.
>> I agree.
>> He's He's the sweetest guy. He means
exactly what he says. He doesn't hold
anything back. Totally honest. Well, I
think it's like you're just a human
being who lives in a country and you're
supposed to have these like things of
what means something and then you start
to see all this stuff that you're like,
well, this goes against everything that
I've learned. This goes against like
>> especially like you grow up like you see
like every other book at the airport is
about the Holocaust for my entire life.
So, it's like every time you're getting
on a plane, you're grabbing one and
you're learning about it and you're like
you you see these things that are wrong
or that are like,
>> you know, and then you see this thing
happening. You're like, how is this? And
then if you mention like and people act
like I I don't know. It's almost like
you feel like you're being just gas lit
and then your media won't cover a lot of
it.
>> That's right.
>> So, I don't know what's going I don't
know. And I don't know what's going on.
>> I was on I was on the Pierce Morgan show
not too long ago. I I go on every couple
of months and I never been on his show.
What's that guy like?
>> Oh, he's he's a good guy, too. And I
have to
>> Is he pretty tall or not?
>> I haven't met him in person actually.
Only on Zoom.
>> Always wondered how tall he was.
Somebody said he was like 5'5. Dude,
>> what?
>> Yeah,
>> that would surprise. 61.
>> 61.
>> Okay, that makes more sense.
>> Maybe the exchange rate on him or
something.
>> Yeah, it's the exchange rate. So, um I
was on his show and I was with um Scott
Horton, who's one of the most brilliant
people I I've ever met. Um and Alan
Dersawitz and uh Danny Ayalon, General
Danny Ayalon, um former former Israeli
general. And when there we are, there we
are. So, uh [laughter]
so when you're on with Dersitz, Duritz
never shuts his mouth.
>> That's it. That was what I was going to
say.
>> Let me see. former C agent John Kirau uh
believes Jeffrey Epson.
>> Oh no, that wasn't it. That's Jeffrey
Epstein. Uh no, it was about it was
about Hamas and Gaza. And he asked me
cuz I had said the least on this episode
and he said, "Do you believe that Hamas
is a terrorist organization?" And I said
I said, "Yes, if the point was on
October 7th was to attack civilians, the
definition of terrorism is the act of
using violence to instill terror in a
civilian population." So that's the
definition of terrorism. So yes, Hamas
is a terrorist organization. He said,
"Uh, do you believe October 7th was a
terrorist attack?" And I said, "Yes." He
said, "Then what are you doing on this
show?" I was supposed to be in the like
anti-Israel, I guess, or whatever. And I
said, "Pice, you can't have as a policy.
Just kill everybody, women, children,
the elderly, wipe out every hospital,
every school, every apartment block.
That's genocide."
>> Yeah.
>> Somebody's got to say it.
Yeah.
I mean, it's scary. And then and then
and then to think, how would our country
be okay right now with us joining
military forces with a group that's
doing that?
>> I'm sure not okay. And then then you
have to ask, what about these people
like Ted Cruz and Lindsey Graham?
Lindsey Graham said the other day, a
week ago, that until I breathe my last
breath, I will stand with Israel. Why?
Why? Oh, that dude's just the N Rochney
of [__] [__]
>> Oh my god. And Cruz is just as bad. And
these clowns from Florida that that wear
IDF uniforms under the floor of the
house. They should be arrested.
>> I didn't even see that.
>> It was Congressman
Fine, but you're like an a you're
supposed to have like a read on these
types of things. Like what do you
think's going on?
>> I think it's Apex money. I think it's
two things. It's Apex money. millions
upon millions and millions of dollars in
American politics.
So they have an inordinate influence on
our political system and Apac is the
only group of its kind that does not
have to register as a foreign agent.
>> You know, I've made a I've made a point
on a couple of podcasts back in 200
like8. I got a very small contract just
I don't know five six thousand bucks to
write four op-eds in support of the Abu
Dhabi Chamber of Commerce. So I wrote
these op-eds. Oh, you should do business
in Abu Dhabi. It's really
businessfriendly. They love Americans.
Everybody makes money. All right, send.
I had to register as a foreign agent
>> because I was uh I was I was publishing
in support of a foreign entity.
>> Interesting. What the heck is APAC doing
24/7?
>> How come they don't have to register as
foreign agents?
>> Yeah. And I I get I think it seems like
we have our our uh our pe our government
officials are afraid to stand up to
them. I don't know why.
>> Very afraid. And then you have these
morons.
>> Why do you think they're afraid? But why
do you think they're afraid?
>> They don't want to be primar.
>> Like even if you get primary, but like
you would eventually somebody will win,
right? Like yes, but but who among them
has the courage to be the first? I mean,
Massie stood up.
>> Massie took it. I I saw him about a week
before the election.
>> But he can't be the only person in
there.
>> Well, Marjorie Taylor Green, but she
didn't have the guts. She quit. She quit
halfway through.
>> What are they What do you think they're
compromising these people? Like, what
are they saying to them? Are they saying
like something bad is going to h like
what do you suggest?
>> They're saying you will never work in
politics ever again.
>> We will hound you for the rest of your
career. Then if you lose then what do
you have any you have nothing to lose
then
>> that's what you and I say you and I
would say would stand up
>> bring up the thing about the just the
government just like the government's
being interacted those two artic that
right uh the house armed services
committee has unveiled its proposed 2027
national defense authorization act which
would see a record shattering $1.15
trillion spent on the US military over
the next fiscal year among the bill's
many provisions is section 224 entitled
the United States Israel defense
technology cooperation ution initiative.
Uh the provision would bring the US and
Israel into an unprecedented partnership
covering technology sharing, the
co-production of weapons systems and
bilateral research and development
across multiple domains of warfare,
including biotech, autonomous systems,
AI, cyber warfare, and more. Well, this
could just mean that we are uh we're
employing technology that they have,
right? Is there any more specifics about
this?
>> Looks closer than that. I'll tell you
what, if
>> and I'm not saying it isn't. Look, it
definitely scares me. I mean, I don't
want to be involved with a country
that's doing something like that. And I
don't think that's crazy for me to say
that either.
>> Even if it's just this,
>> um, that means they're not going to have
to steal the 2% of defense technology
that we don't give them. I'll give you
an example. When I was still there, we
were developing the F-35. So, they came
to us, they said, "We want the F-35. We
want want to be the first ones to have
the F-35." We said, "Great. We're going
to have we're going to give you the
F-35. We're going to call it the F-35i
for Israel. And it's going to have just
a barely slightly degraded um avionics
system just in case, god forbid, you
know, it doesn't get shot down and then
the Chinese and the Russians get it and
then they can steal the avionics. They
said, "No, not good enough. We want the
we want the F-35, the same one that you
guys fly." In the meantime, the Emirates
came to us and they said, "We want the
F-35." We said, "Great. We're going to
give you the F-35E. we're going to call
it for Emirates and it's going to have
just a slightly degraded avionics
package. Same thing we're giving the
Israelis. They said, "Fine, we'll take
it." The Israelis
then tasked their spies with stealing
whatever the downgrade was in the in the
avionics so that they could re-upgrade
it once they took delivery of the F-35.
Well, now we're just going to share
everything with them. We'll just give
them the F35.
>> But can you like can you fault a
country? Like it's kind of interesting
cuz
I think if you if you think that we're
playing like that the I I guess I always
felt like we were out of the
colonization era.
>> I know. I'm with you.
>> And and
>> and I know what you're getting at.
>> And so it's like you can't fault a
country really for just trying to
survive.
>> I don't. I don't.
>> And I'm not saying you are. I'm think
I'm thinking out loud. But let me finish
the sentence real quick. Sorry, John.
But yeah, you can't f like, you know, if
a country is just trying to survive and
they're good at it and better at it than
others, then it's like that has to be
respected in in some senses for sure.
Agreed. I don't fault the Israelis for
doing this. If I were the prime minister
of Israel, I would do the same thing
when it comes to acquiring defense
technology. I fault the US government.
And it makes not one wit of difference
if there's a Democrat in the White House
or a Republican in the White House. We
don't stand up to the Israelis.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, I will say Reagan did in the
so-called year of the spy when Jonathan
Pard was uh No, actually it wasn't
Reagan by then. It was Clinton, wasn't
it?
Clinton stood up and said, "We're going
to prosecute this guy." Pard
>> peaked in ' 84. Jonathan,
>> when was he arrested?
>> 85. Okay. So, it was Reagan. It was
Reagan. He did every single day of the
30 years. And um then when he got out of
prison,
Miriam Adlesen or not Mary Mson, her
husband, it was uh what's his name?
Aden, uh the the king of Las Vegas
>> sent his private jet. The jet took Pard
to Israel. Netanyahu met him at the
airport. He kissed the ground. And in an
interview, Sheldon Eden in an interview
he urged American Jews to take up arms
against the American government
and then Huckabe meets with him and
welcomes him into the American embassy.
I would have shot him if he had come
into the American embassy and I were the
ambassador.
>> Yeah. I just don't understand. I think
it makes it like I don't know. I think a
lot of people are looking for guidance
right now.
>> I think you're right. If you're a
regular person who we're just trying to
get through the week, we want to believe
in our country. We get scared that our
taxes are going towards like
>> Yes. violent things and evil things.
That's the thing. It starts to feel like
there's something evil going on. Um
>> Yeah. And it's not like
>> we're right and everybody else in the
rest of the world is wrong. You know,
you look at these votes. I don't know if
I'm right about anything. [laughter] You
You look at these votes at the UN
General Assembly and it's everybody in
the world voting yes and voting no is
the United States. I'm serious about
this because I served at the UN. It's
the United States, Israel, Costa Rica,
and Palao.
A little island with 30,000 people in
the Pacific. That's it. And the whole
rest of the world is voting the other
way.
You've talked a like you've worked on
counterterrorism.
Is it weird? Like terrorism is such an
interesting term because it's like at a
certain point it feels like we're
chasing the tail of the dog we let loose
kind of. Does that make any sense even?
>> Yeah, I like that. I might steal that.
>> Yeah, steal it. I don't even know
exactly what it means, but um you know
they just had a they I saw something the
other It was like uh $300 billion to
rebuild um
parts of I don't think it's Iran, but I
think it's Libya.
>> Can you look that up? 300 billion to
rebuild parts of Libya
>> that we that we
>> that we just that we just blew up.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, right here it says a truce $300
billion investment plan in Hormuz.
What's in the deal draft that can end US
Iran war? US and Iran mediators are now
engaged in high stakes negotiations
aimed at ending the conflict despite a
fragile ceasefire in the place and
months of turmoil in the Middle East.
The possible truce plan includes key
bargaining points between these two two
sides including a $300 billion
investment package uh and the crucial
straight of hormonal issue making the
agreement extremely closely watched for.
However, one of the biggest developments
emerging from the discussions is a
proposed multi-billion dollar
reconstruction and investment package
that could fundamentally reshape Iran's
economy if a final deal is reached. So,
it's just why it's like we just went
there and got involved in this. I don't
know if this is a taxpayer thing.
>> God, I hope not.
>> But just the whole thing is like uh I
don't know. You start to feel so
defeated sometimes.
>> Yeah. Isn't that the truth?
>> And you start to feel like your vote
isn't going to do anything. Um, that's
the scary part. And then part of this
feels like a long-term SCOP. Like it's a
slow weakening of the values. like,
okay, let's put things in this society
over time that'll like, you know, tear
apart the American family and like
that'll like poison people and let's do
you think there like
>> there's big scops like that going on
like let's put CO out there so that uh
people are separate from each other and
um and that people can't go to meetings
and meet up and so you start to
deteriorate the value of human
connection and uh let's po let's make
food so that it's just poisoning people
and that it's um you know that it's it's
just going to you know it's going to
make people sick or let's make health
care so it's not there's no real way uh
besides extreme stress that you have to
go through if you even have to make a
claim like you know do you think that uh
some of that is just corporate greed and
stuff or do you think some of that's a
longer term scop by like bigger powers
out there?
>> I I don't I I don't think it's a part of
a bigger SCOP. Okay. Um, but I do
believe firmly that it's mostly
corporate greed. You just reminded me of
something I excuse me I saw recently.
>> Um, and it was this experiment that I
don't know somebody did. I saw it on
YouTube where they put a they they put a
homemade um hamburger on the ground and
they put a a McDonald's quarter pounder
on the ground and then they photographed
it, you know, over the course of days
and then weeks and then months.
Bugs come, ants come, they they go to
the to the hamburger, they tear the bun
down. Mostly they went for the meat, but
they end up, you know, a week later it's
just a spot on the sidewalk. Even bugs
won't touch a McDonald's hamburger.
>> And then months later it's it looks like
it just came out of the package.
>> Yeah.
>> And Europeans can't understand how we
eat like that.
>> Yeah.
>> Like the their laws are different.
McDonald's can't do that in in European
countries.
>> Yeah. Let's look at the ingredients
right here. The difference between uh
McDonald's Europe and um McDonald's
America. 10 plus ingredients versus four
ingredients.
>> Wow. So, the US has 10 plus ingredients
and yeah, Europe has four uh ingredients
in the US. Potatoes, vegetable oil, uh
hydrogenated soybean oil, natural beef
flavor, wheat and milk derivatives,
dextrose, sodium acid, f pyroso,
pyroate, pyro, and salt.
>> Pyrophosphate.
>> Pyrophosphate. Thank you. And then
Europe has potatoes, non-hydrogenated
oil, uh, rape cedar, sunflower, and
dextrose.
>> And look below that, contains
hydrogenated oils, beef flavoring, and
TBHQ, which are banned restricted in EU.
[laughter]
These are for the French fries. It says
contains hydrogenated oils, beef
flavoring, TBHQ.
Uh, and then it says for Europe that
those are those exactly things are
banned and restricted in the EU. Um,
what about the burger? Yeah. What does
it say?
The US beef is 100% pure beef. The
additives several hundred additives.
Several hundred additives
>> prohibited in EU.
And uh, let me see. Europe says 100%
beef from British Irish farmers. No
hormone treated beef. And then uh, the
additives are stricter quality control
and fewer additives.
>> Look at look at the big big mac. The
special sauce on the Big Mac contains
HFCS, zantham gum, propyline, glycol,
algenate, and caramel color. What the
[__] Why? I I just like at some at some
point you have to be like, what
happened? You know, um and while the
Europe uh Big Mac sauce contains simpler
ingredients list uh and 40 fewer
calories, it says um
the differences are EU food regulations
are much stricter. Uh customer
preferences and local supply chains
vary. Um and the US fries would likely
be illegal to sell in Europe due to
ingredient restrictions.
>> Have you ever seen what's in the McRib?
>> I tell you what, I I loved those McRibs.
>> Well, the black community goes bonkers
when they come back. I know that
>> you rush to McDonald's for McRib, but
then when you see what's in it, you're
like, "Oh my god." Well, yeah, dude.
Anybody thinking it has anything to do
with a [__] animal, the McRib? But at
a certain point, we are also guilty.
>> Yeah, we are.
>> It's like if I Yeah. It's our own
laziness and we give in and we just go
do it.
>> That's a big part of it. So that's
what's interesting too right now. It's
like there's a real test of like
>> what do I you know how much do I want to
stand up for myself and but then also
how much can I some people are trapped
financially by certain abilities and
restrictions deserts.
>> Yeah.
>> So it's [snorts] just kind of
interesting. It's tough. Um, and I don't
want to get all super dower. Um, what uh
do you feel like there are a lot of uh
foreign agents in America right now?
>> Oh, yeah. In fact, there's an
advertisement that you see on the sides
of buses around Washington saying that
and and it's the the advertisement is to
visit the spy museum that there are
between 10 and 15,000
foreign intelligence officers in
Washington DC.
>> In Washington DC. more than anywhere
else on the planet.
>> Wow. Do you think that's real?
>> There's a spy on this bus.
>> Oh, that's what that advertisement says.
>> It's part of the Thank you, Edward
Snowden. Um, it's part of the
advertising campaign. Yeah.
>> And is a campaign to to what? To hire
more of them.
>> No, no. To get people to go to the spy
museum.
>> Oh, it's to get them to go to the spy
museum. Dude, I've been to the spy
museum before. It's awesome.
>> It's great.
>> Spy museum's so good.
>> Yeah, it's really great. I agree. Times
were different back in the day when it
was like you'd like be like using a
secret pen or like you'd have a homing
pigeon with like a little backpack on.
>> No, now it's all so crazy sophisticated.
I was just telling somebody the other
day um about uh the the uh CIA trained
cats to wander onto the Soviet embassy
compound with collars that had listening
devices on them just to see what the
Russians were saying when they come out
of the embassy. But that didn't work
because you can't train the cats. So
they trained pigeons and they put little
listening devices around their pigeon
little pigeon feet um and they would
land on the window sills. But the thing
is that the Russians had double pane
glass and they were piping music in
between the two panes of glass so the
pigeons couldn't hear anything.
>> No way. [laughter]
What a game. Like what a game of like uh
espionage, huh?
>> That's so much fun.
>> That's so See, that kind of stuff is so
exciting. Now it feels like um I don't
know. It feels like we're entering
sometimes like a surveillance state or
>> We are. We are. It's not like the old
days. You know, one of the best
recruitments I ever made, Theo.
I was doing surveillance on this guy for
a week. I I thought, you know, this guy
would be an interesting target. He
doesn't have he doesn't make much money.
Um
>> Oh, you were doing surveillance on a
guy?
>> On a guy.
>> And what does that mean? You're doing
surveillance. You're like you're
wandering around in the distance.
>> Yes, that's exactly what it means. Yeah.
You're just wandering around the
distance. Watch him every day. see where
he goes, what he does, where he hangs
out, who he talks to. His his wife had
left him. But I noticed he walked his
dog every morning at 6:30.
>> Dang.
>> Every morning he'd leave the house at
6:30 and he would walk across the park.
The dog would do his business and then
he'd walk back. So I asked in the
office, I said, "Hey, does anybody have
a dog?" And one of the women's like,
"Yeah, I have a dog." I said, "Can I
borrow your dog for a week?" She says,
"For what?" I said, 'I want to I want to
accidentally bump into this guy and
while he's walking his dog, I want to
walk your dog and then I meet him and
I'm going to say hello and then the next
day I'm going to say hello again. Then
the third day I'm going to invite him to
lunch and whatever. It was the best
recruitment I ever made in my entire
career and we bonded over the dogs and
it wasn't even my dog. At the end of the
week I just gave her a dog back.
>> And did you learn something from the
guy? Oh my god.
This guy was like every case officer's
dream recruitment.
>> And what recruitment means? Somebody
that you're just you're get trying to
gain intel from
>> the the person you he you pitch him. You
say, "Look, I'm with the CIA."
>> Oh, you're pay you told him that.
>> Oh, yeah. I'm with the CIA. I know who
you are. I know what you do and I'm
willing to pay you very handsomely to
give it to me. And he's like, "How
handsome is handsome?"
And I gave him a number.
>> What's that number, ballpark? Well,
>> this is 25 years ago and then it was
$5,000 a month. It would probably be
20,000 a month now. And um
>> good money.
>> And he wanted all of his expenses. I
said, "What expenses do you think you're
going to have?"
>> Yeah.
>> What dog shots for the dog?
>> I know, right? So, oh, he nickel and
dime the expenses. And my boss would
always say, "Just just give it to him.
Just give it to him." Because the
information was so great. So we had
>> information about what?
>> His country.
>> Oh.
>> He worked in the embassy.
>> Got it.
>> Of his country. And uh
>> I gave him a disposable cell phone. And
back then you had to buy these little
cards at the convenience store and you
scratch them off and you put the number
in your phone and it gives you units.
You know,
>> remember that?
>> And um
>> so the phone was only supposed to be
used to call me. He used it for
everything. He'd give me like $800 phone
bills at the end of the month. And I'm
like, "Come on, man. Come on.
>> That's awesome.
>> Five grand already.
>> That dude's a freaking snake. I love
that."
>> Yeah, my boss. Just Just pay it. Just
pay it. Acoustic Kitty.
>> Oh my gosh. Oh, it's an Oh, Acoustic
Kitty was a Central Intelligence Agency
project launched by the Directorate of
Science and Technology in the 1960s. It
was intended to use cats to spy on the
Kremlin and Soviet embassies. In an
hour-long procedure, a veterinary
surgeon implanted a microphone in the
cat's ear canal, a small radio
transmitter at the base of its skull.
Dear God, and a thin wire into its fur.
This would allow the cat to innocuously
record and transmit sound from its
surroundings. Due to problems with
distraction, the cat's sense of hunger.
>> It sees a bird had to be addressed in
another operation. [laughter]
>> $20 million. $20 million, dude. And
that's your Somali fraud right there.
The first acoustic hitting mission was
to eve drop on two men in a park outside
the Soviet embassy in Washington DC. The
cat was released nearby but was hit and
allegedly killed by a taxi almost
immediately.
However, this was disputed. Uh the
equipment was taken out of the cat. The
cat was resone for a second time and
lived a long and happy life afterwards.
That sounds like a cover up.
>> Nothing to see here, folks. Yeah,
[laughter] just a cat that has call
waiting, you know? That's a [__]
insane dude. I worked with this one guy
who was going to a denied area. A denied
area is a place where CIA people just
can't go, right? But he looked kind of
ethnic and he could fit into, you know,
whatever the culture. And so I said,
"Buddy, aren't you afraid of uh like
being kidnapped and then we just never
see you again?" And he said, "Yeah, they
offered to implant a a a a chip, a
beacon that a ping in my butt crack," he
says. And I said, "No, leave my butt
crack alone." Yeah. Yeah, that's Yeah,
that's fair. I think that should be our
national anthem. [laughter]
Um,
how weary do people have to be of uh
being spied up on today? Do you think
like there's a lot of these new like
data center projects
>> and stuff like that that's going on with
that? Um
>> first let's talk Yeah. real quick about
the data centers. What do you think is
really going on? Because if you look at
the the size of these places
>> like we don't need that much. Like we're
already using our phones. We're already
have like um televisions like that you
know there's already like a lot of stuff
being stored um on servers. How are we
jumping to a level where we need that?
That's what I want to know.
>> Oh, I have to agree. Besides the fact
that they use massive amounts of water
and oddly enough they're located in a
lot of states that don't have a ton of
water like Texas. Yeah. Or you go out to
uh Lowden County, Virginia. Okay, we
have enough water. But Lowden County,
Virginia, you drive for miles and miles
and they're just these neverending
gigantic complexes of data centers. The
proposed Stratos project in Utah is a
massive 40,000 water in Utah. a 40,000
acre AI data center campus. Um, two and
a half times larger than Manhattan.
>> Yeah. [clears throat]
I wonder how long the actual data how
big
>> and and just the data center requires
more than double the current energy
consumption of the entire state of Utah.
>> Yeah.
>> Come on.
>> I mean, that's unbelievable. What do you
think's really going on there? Do you
have any intel about it?
>> You have to assume that this is Intel
related because look at the the
companies that are involved. We're
talking about Palunteer and Nvidia and
Arais and all these these big companies
that either took CIA investments to get
started as seed money or um or are
staffed by retired senior CIA officers.
They're not doing it for their health.
Why is the C so is the CIA now is spying
on our own people. Oh yeah, that's what
Ed Snowden warned us about. Yeah,
without Ed Snowden's revelations, we
wouldn't have any idea that NSA and CIA
were spying on Americans, which is not
just illegal, it's a part of NSA's
charter that it may not spy on
Americans.
And this place in Utah,
um, he and Julian Assange told us about
Utah. This new compound in Utah that NSA
has built has enough memory storage
space for every phone call, every email,
and every text message from every
American for the next 500 years.
>> Wow.
>> Why?
>> Just that building.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Then why do they need all these
buildings?
>> Yeah. Why? They're everywhere. What are
they collecting?
>> I'm not sure. And that's it's like what
it must be. It's got to be all of our
information.
What would you do right now? Is there
any way that people can protect
themselves? Do you know? It's almost
impossible now. I I wrote a series of
books during COVID for Skyers
Publishing, The CIA Insiders Guides to
Surveillance and Surveillance Detection,
uh Lying and Lie Detection and
Disappearing and Living Off the Grid.
They put them together and they're
republishing them in the next month, I
guess,
>> um as one volume. CIA skills, tactics,
and the ultimate guide to CIA skills,
tactics, and techniques.
>> There we go.
>> But when it comes to protecting yourself
from from, you know, the data state, you
got to go Eric Rudolph or Uni Bomber and
just own no technology at all. It's the
only way to protect yourself. Otherwise,
you're going to be scooped up in all
this. Now, the odd thing is according to
Ed Snowden, uh, NSA, CIA,
other governmental organizations are
scooping up all this data and they're
just holding it.
Why? Why are they holding it? Now, time
was really until the immediate post 911
uh period where if the government wanted
your information, they had to go to a
federal judge and say, "We want TheoN's
information, and this is the reason we
want it." And the judge had to say,
"Okay, that's a legitimate reason. I'll
sign the warrant." Now, they just write
something called a national security
letter. They give it to your provider
and they say, "Give us everything you
have on Theoon." And they just turn it
over. [clears throat] or they go to
these new data centers and uh and just
put your name in, your information, and
everything pops up. They don't even you
don't have any legal protections. They
just take whatever they want. And that's
legal now. They can do that.
>> And it's legal now. How'd that become
legal?
>> In the National Defense Act of of 2016,
National Defense Authorization Act of
2016.
>> Wow. Yeah. Which also, this is a a pet
peeve of mine that nobody knows about.
It also for the first time in American
history allowed the American government
to propagandize the American people. It
was always illegal for our government to
propagandize us.
>> What does it mean?
>> Well, for example, the Voice of America,
that's our government's propaganda news
outlet and we beam it overseas so
everybody gets the official US point of
view. Okay.
Back in the in the 80s, the Reagan
administration came up with with these
two broadcasters called uh Radio Marty
and TV Marty to beam at Cuba.
>> The Cubans try to jam them all the time.
But what they mostly are used for is uh
to broadcast baseball games in Spanish,
which the Cubans love. Got it. I flew
down to Cuba to to do a study. I did a
study for the Senate Foreign Relations
Committee when I was the chief
investigator there. And um
nobody watches TV Marty. You can only
actually get it in the waiting room of
the US consulate. Got it. So if you're
there to apply for a visa, you can watch
a soap opera in Spanish. That's American
propaganda. Nobody cares. The radio
people like listening in baseball.
So, Dish Network when it began
when it began selling um services in
Florida found that there was this just
narrow swath along the shore on the on
the west coast of Florida where you
could pick up TV marty. That's illegal.
You can't propagandize the American
people. Got it.
>> As Americans, we're not allowed to watch
our own government's propaganda.
So instead of telling Dish Network,
well, you're going to have to like move
your satellite or do something or
pixelate it or whatever, said, "No, no,
no. We'll change the law." And so in the
National Defense Authorization Act of
2016, the Obama administration said,
"No, no, we can propagandize Americans
now." Wow. And so now radio, TV are no
problem.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> But I mean, we're always propagandizing.
I mean, people put out propaganda all
the time. Yeah, I went to Yemen in 2011
uh when I was with the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee. My fifth trip to
Yemen. Every time I'd go to Yemen, it's
worse than the previous time. So, I have
a meeting with the defense atache. And
he was so proud of this thing that he
was doing, this SCOP. I hate that word,
SCOP. I said, "Sure, what's your what's
your SCOP?" and he goes, "We're funding
a radio station here modeled on NPR
and it plays American jazz and then it
has a call-in show so young Yemen guys
can call in and talk about the jazz."
I'm like, "What the [__] are you talking
about? That's a terrible idea. Nobody's
going to listen to that." And nobody did
and they shut it down after a year. But
that's that's what we're doing. But what
was the goal of it even? to make people
pro-American because they would be like,
"Oh, Americans have jazz."
>> Oh, I see.
>> So, I'm gonna be pro-American now. It's
like, what are you thinking? You You sit
there like money laundering.
>> Yeah. Seriously,
>> that's what it sounds like. Um, how do I
know I can believe you about anything
kind of people ask you that all the
time?
>> Oh, yeah. People ask me all the time.
Um,
>> cuz who would believe anybody that is
XCIA? Who would even, you know what I'm
saying?
>> Oh, that's such a thing with me.
You know, generally I don't read the
chats anywhere, right?
>> Mhm. Everybody I talk to at your level,
you Tucker Carlson, you know, Patrick
Bet David Rogan, whomever, they never
read the chats. Sometimes I can't help
it. And I'll scan them. The only time I
ever respond is when people say, "Once
CIA, always CIA,
>> [__] You thought you thought all of
that all up on your own, huh?"
>> That's true. That's true.
>> So I said I said to one guy, I said,
"You know what? Let me call Ed Snowden
and the sons of Philip Ag and Ray
McGovern and tell them that you think
they're all still in the CIA.
>> So I went to prison for telling the
truth. And I would [clears throat] I
would do it again in a heartbeat. In a
heartbeat. Nobody else has gone to
prison for ratting out the CIA and its
illegal, you know, programs. I was proud
to do it.
>> That's a good answer.
>> Thank you. It's a really good answer. If
you look, [laughter] here it is. And I
can say this. If you really went to jail
and everything, then it's a great
answer. And if you did,
>> I believe you. I believe you. But also,
there's a little part of me that's like,
if he didn't, then that's [__] even
colder that he's making it up and living
it. That's the most CIA [__]
>> That would be pretty intense.
>> But that's what I'm saying.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, nobody in the world
hates me as much as my ex-wife does
>> from spending all that time in the CIA
or in jail. At least jail you have a
good excuse after. But she came every
month with the kids and visited me in
jail for two years.
>> Yeah.
>> And so why does she hate you then?
>> Oh, no. That's that's all Yeah. Post
story post. Yeah. I'm actually
prohibited by court order from answering
that question. [laughter]
>> Well, that's I think that's amazing that
she did that and brought your kids.
>> She was she was great. She was great.
>> A lot of wives. I mean, I think that's I
can't even imagine it's a tough thing
for families, especially if you had
young children. Um,
kudos to her for that.
>> Yeah.
>> Um,
was bringing in prison kind of fun.
>> Um, fun.
>> No, I No, I wouldn't say fun.
>> Like what was kind of cool about it.
I've always wanted to go to jail.
>> You know, there there's this old saying
that you don't go to jail to make
friends. And I made some lifelong
friends in jail. Um, mostly named
Gambino, Lucesy, Banano. Yeah. Okay.
Genevese.
>> So, a lot of good storytellers in there,
I bet. [gasps]
>> Listen, those guys were so honorable.
I learned so much from those guys in
just 23 months.
>> Wow.
>> Uh, lessons I'll carry with me forever.
Real honor. It's funny. The Italians
were the smallest. They call them gangs
in prison. The Italians weren't a gang.
This is I'll I'll use the word gang just
for the purpose of this response. They
were the smallest gang in the prison yet
commanded the highest level of respect
>> really more than the blacks and the
Latinos.
>> The blacks and the Latinos were always
at at each other's throats and they had
like for example it was Crips and Bloods
and there was this uneasy piece between
them just because it's not worth
upsetting the apple cart and everybody
goes to solitary and then gets spread
out all over the country. For the
Latinos, it was far more complicated
because it was Burachos, Nortenos, Latin
Kings, MS-13,
um, Mexican mafia, and then the
individual cartels.
So, overall, there's one gigantic
Hispanic prison gang called Pisces, and
then within Pisces are all the different
divisions.
>> Gosh.
>> Yeah. And the Pisces, if you were
Hispanic, you were automatically in
Pisces, whether you liked it or not. And
you had to work out every single day.
>> Oh, that's pretty good.
>> For the coming race war with the blacks,
>> right? And the whites are like, uh, we
have nothing to do with this.
>> Yeah. I just want to I would just want
to do it just to get in shape. But
>> yeah. Yeah.
>> Sometimes you need motivation.
>> We had we had Aryan Brotherhood.
>> What's that? What are they doing? What
are they up to?
>> You know, Aryan Brotherhood of Texas is
far more violent than Aryan Brotherhood.
And they're not It says right there.
They're not connected. Um, I never met
anybody from the Aryan Brotherhood of
Texas. Aryan Brotherhood at a low
security prison just wants to sort of,
you know, go along to get along.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. You stay out of my way. I'll stay
out of yours. My very first day in
prison, my very first hour in prison
when the when the guard dropped me off
in my cell, the only thing he said to me
the whole time I was, you know, checking
in and getting processed was, "If
somebody comes into your cell uninvited,
that's an act of aggression." And I
said, "Great. Thank you. I've been here
40 minutes. I'm going to get my ass
kicked now."
>> Sure enough, as soon as he left, these
two guys walked into my cell. Just
walked right in. One of them had a
swastika that took up his entire neck
and then came up onto his face and the
other one had [__] you tattooed on his
eyelids.
>> Oh yeah, that check. I mean that's Yeah.
>> And so I jump up. I go, "What do you
want?"
>> Cuz I thought, you know, if I'm going
down, I'm taking one of them down with
me at least. What do you want?
>> And the the one with the swastika says,
"You the new guy?" I go, "Yeah." So
>> this [laughter] is like a This sounds
like a story from like the 1940s.
>> Awful.
I I said in my second book, "Prison is a
combination of seventh grade, the Lord
of the Flies, and a mental institution."
And it's set in the 1950s.
>> That's hilarious.
>> So I go, "What do you want?" He's he
goes, "You the new guy?" I said, "Yeah,
so." And he goes, "I'm standing there
like this." He goes, "You a" And I go,
"No, I'm not a He says," and they were
bummed out. "You a rat?" "No, no, no
gays allowed." "You a rat?" And I said,
"No, I'm not a rat. you a chomo? I go, I
don't know what that word means.
[laughter]
He goes, chomo, child molester. I said,
no, I'm not a child molester.
>> That's good.
>> And then he says, you can sit with the
Aryans in the cafeteria. And I was like,
oh,
>> well, yeah, I guess I'm I'm with the
Aryans now. But then a couple of months
later, simple rules.
>> I was across the hall from from a
captain in the Banano family
>> and he said to me one day, he goes, "Let
me ask you a question.
Why do you sit with those Nazi retards
every day? And I said, I don't know. I
said, my first day here, they just told
me to sit with them. And he goes, from
today, you are with the Italians.
>> I said, it's about time.
>> That was it. Yeah.
>> Took you long enough.
>> You got drafted.
>> Yeah. But they were the best.
>> Yeah. I bet a lot of good stories, dude.
Any good story come to mind from
somebody you like a good story you heard
in uh in prison?
>> Yeah, there's there's one. I'm actually
You're gonna think less of me and I
don't care.
>> That's fine. I could tell you some stuff
that would probably make it even.
>> There was a guy in my housing unit who
was a serial killer. He was called truck
because he drove long-distance trucks
from the east coast to the west coast
and he would pick up prostitutes at uh
>> truck stops and he would rape them and
murder them, drive them a couple of
hundred miles down the highway and then
dump the bodies out. So
>> the cops estimated that he killed 14. It
was probably more than that, but um he
strangled one and she survived and she
was able to give the cops the license
number. Now this was in the days before
DNA training, did DNA testing.
>> So this guy
>> before DNA testing.
>> Yeah. This was in the 70s.
>> Oh, he'd been in for a long time.
>> He was doing life.
>> Got it.
>> So um for reasons that were never clear
to me, this guy constantly sought my
approval. He was full of [__] He would
come up. He had the worst breath because
he had just these blackened rotten nubs
where his that used to be his teeth. And
he was saying [snorts] [__] dicks all
day. It was awful. Awful. He goes, "You
CIA?" And I said, "Yeah, I used to be."
He goes, "I did work for the CIA. I ran
a shrimp boat full of weapons to
Angola." I go, "Get the [__] out of
here." I didn't know he was a serial
killer. I go, "Get the [__] out of here.
Shrimp boat to Angola. Have you ever
been on a shrimp boat?" and I walked
away. [snorts] People are looking at me
like, "Are you crazy? Do you know who
that is?" Well, I didn't know who it
was. So, um,
instead of making him mad, it just made
him more actively seek my approval.
>> So, I'm a big Pittsburgh Steelers fan.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> And, um, he would say, "Hey, John, the
Steelers are the game of the featured
game of the week. I saved you a seat in
the TV room." I'm like, "Ah, thanks,
Truck." Like, okay. John, uh, I I know
you listen to classic rock. there's a
new classic rock station 1600 AM. You
should check it out. I'm like, okay,
thanks, Truck. In the meantime, there's
this guy we called Cat in the Hat.
Because he had this oddly elongated
head, like a birth defect, kind of giant
Cat in the Hat head,
and he comes up to me one day and he
said, "Hey, I heard you had a an empty
bunk in your in your cell. I want to
move into your cell. I heard it's a good
cell." And I said, "Well, not so fast,
buddy." I said, "We don't allow any
pedophiles in our cell and no rats." I
said, 'What's your crime? He goes,
"Murder for hire and no." I don't even
care about that.
>> Yeah, the other guys I can't speak for
the other guys.
>> Yeah, I was trying to like I was trying
to be a part of the group, you know,
like go on, go on. [laughter]
So, uh,
so he says, uh, I murder for hire. I
said, I don't think I like that any
better than the pedophiles of the rats.
What What were the circumstances? And he
said, I owed the mob a lot of money,
hundred,000 in gambling. I couldn't pay
it. So, I took out a life insurance
policy on my business partner and I
hired a hitman to kill him and uh and
the hitman got uh got caught. I said,
"Let me think about it." Well, think
about it. I went straight to the law
library and I looked up his case. And
that wasn't it at all. It was true. He
owed the mob 100,000. He took out the
life insurance policy. He hired the
hitman. He got caught because of course
he's going to get caught. Where the
where's the first place the cops are
going to go?
>> Where the money went. and he ratted out
the hitman so that he wouldn't get the
federal death penalty. Instead, he got
20 years. So, I said, "No rats in the
room."
So, he was mad at me. Anyway, one day
Jake Tapper comes up to the prison to
interview me and I get called down to
the lieutenant's office. Normally, if
you're called down the lieutenant's
office, it's to go to solitary. If you
come back, usually it's because you
ratted somebody out. Well, I went down
there to sign the the waiver so I could
give Jake Tapper the interview.
So, I'm sitting in the TV room next to
Truck. Truck was very, very sensitive
about being called a Chomo cuz that girl
that he strangled was 16, which
technically made him a Chomo. Right.
Right. So, Truck's sitting here. I'm
sitting here. Right here is Cat in the
Hat with his back toward me. He's on the
computer. There's like this internal
internet, not internet, internal email
system. He doesn't see me. I'm sitting
18 in away from him. And then he says to
the guy next to him, "Do you hear?
Kiryaku got called down to the
lieutenants office." He goes, "That
guy's a [__] rat. He went down there
to rat us out." And I just sat there
watching the game. And then Truck says,
"That [__] guy just called you a
rat." And I said, "An hour ago, I heard
him call you a cho." Which was a total
lie. I just made it up. He didn't say a
single word. He just stood up, walked
over here, and beat this guy almost to
death.
They had to land a helicopter in the
yard to lifellight Cat in the Hat to
Pittsburgh.
>> They gave truck five more years and Cat
Scan in the Hat, huh?
>> Yeah. Yeah, it's Cat Scan in the Hat.
See? [clears throat] How come I didn't
think of that? Cuz I'm not a comedian. I
should have put that in my book.
>> I don't know. Is there any real value in
me thinking of that? That's a good
question. I don't 6 weeks later, Cat in
the Hat is finally released from the
hospital. He comes, he's all [__] up
still. And um and he's like this.
Somebody had told him what had happened.
He he goes, "I I wanted to say I'm sorry
for calling you a rat. I should never
have said that." And everybody is stops
to look to see what I'm going to say.
Well, what am I going to say? Ah, forget
it. It's all water under the bridge. I
go, "Listen, look at me. Look at me."
And he lifts his head up and I said, "So
help me God. If I ever hear my name
cross your lips ever again, you're dead
and there won't even find you." I'm
sorry. I'm sorry. So everybody's like,
"Ah,
the CIA guy's tough after all." But I
said in the book, one of my rules that I
learned at the CIA, let others do your
dirty work. And then I get called down
to the lieutenant's office again because
as he's beating him, I sat back down.
I'm watching the game. Everybody else
runs. As soon as there's a fight,
everybody just runs like cockroaches.
>> Insane though, man.
>> Right. So, I'm watching the game.
Keryaku lieutenants office immediately.
They always do it the same way. It's
like a they're caricatures of
themselves.
>> So, I go down there and the one of the
lieutenants, there are two of them, and
he says, "So, tell us about this fight."
I go, "What fight? What fight? You're
going to be a smart guy now." I said, "I
don't know what the [__] you're talking
about." The fight. We had four cameras
showing you saying something
>> to that crazy person and then he got up
and beat the other guy. I said, "I was
watching the Steelers game. I don't know
what you're talking about." Oh, you're
not going to tell us about the fight? I
said, you know what? Maybe I will tell
you about the fight. Maybe it was you
that started the fight. Did you ever
think of that? Maybe it wasn't me. I was
an innocent bystander. Maybe you put
them up to fight each other. I think I
might make a complaint against you. He
goes, "Get the [__] out of my office."
And I wrote in my book, "Rule number
one, admit nothing. Deny everything.
Make counter accusations."
>> And as I was walking out, I just said,
"Exactly.
Dang, bro. I don't even know what to
think anymore." [laughter]
>> You know, I think
>> sometimes that's where you get people to
that point. you're like this, you know,
>> they pushed me and pushed me and pushed
me and at sentencing, the judge
sentenced me to a minimum security work
camp and the CIA was furious that I got
such a light sentence and I was going to
a minimum security camp. So, the CIA
intervened to send me to a media uh
sorry, a low security prison, which is
an actual prison with the double, you
know, walls.
>> They were furious that I
>> Yeah, it was. When I was first charged,
I mean, this is a potential death
penalty case. Three counts of espionage
for talking to ABC News and the New York
Times
>> because you were talking to him about
about uh torture, right?
>> Mhm.
>> What cases specifically were you talking
to him about?
>> Abu Zuba.
>> And they were furious because nobody had
ever confirmed that there was a torture
program. And I said, "It was illegal."
Besides being immoral and unethical,
it's illegal. You want to torture
people, God bless, but you got to change
the law first. We're a nation of laws.
>> Which countries do you think had the mo
the like the toughest torture programs
over the years?
>> Or do you even know?
>> Over the years, like let's go back a
hundred years. the Chinese, the
Vietnamese, and the Belgians.
The Belgians, if you can imagine, the
the horrors that they perpetrated in
Congo
of of epic proportions.
Um,
yeah, the Russians, the Iranians, the
Israelis, the United States.
Is it weird like because we talked about
the term terrorism now, but it's like it
definitely feels like when we talked
about it a few a little bit earlier,
it's like it feels sometimes it's like
how much is America like a terrorist
state in the world? And I hate to say
that because this is the country that we
live in, but it's like I think at a
certain point if you use
it, you know, I don't know. I don't
know. You know, it's got to be hard to
figure that out. But it's like um
[clears throat]
you know it's like when do you use like
fear tactics and and that sort of thing
to make sure that everything's okay, you
know. Um
yeah, I don't know. It's like do you
Here's my question. Do you think it's
possible for America to get to a place
uh where we're an actual peacekeeper or
do you think it's possible to keep peace
without terror?
That make any sense or not? Yeah, that's
a hard question.
>> Good.
>> You know, and and I think my answer has
changed over the years.
>> I believed for a very long time that we
were the good guys. I was a true
believer. That's why I worked there. We
were the good guys and we still I think
as people we still are citizens we still
are.
>> Agreed. Agreed. We still are. Somebody
commented on a Facebook post that I made
the other day like, uh, I heard you say
that the United States is the best
country in the world. You should be
ashamed of yourself. I was like, I
believe that the United States is the
best country in the world. That's why I
live here. Yeah,
>> I could go live in some other country if
I wanted to, but this is the best
country in the world. We have problems.
Every country has problems. But the
reason why I'm as active and as vocal as
I am is because I want to change the
things that I disagree with. I don't
think we should be a nation that
tortures people or murders people
without trial. If somebody is a clear
and present danger, which is the
language that's used in the amendment to
1233,
okay, clear and present danger. They're
getting ready to, you know, deliver the
dirty bomb or, you know, whatever. Okay.
Sometimes we have to work in the
shadows. Awful. But it but it's a fact
of life. But if you just send teams
around the world to kill people whose
politics you don't like, people who have
never been charged with a crime, then
shame on us. That's not what the
founding fathers gave us. So if you want
to torture people, you got to change the
law. Ronald Reagan said we were a
shining city on a hill, right? We're a a
beacon of hope for human rights and
civil rights and civil liberties. That's
the country I want to be.
>> Same. That's what most people want to
be.
>> Exactly.
>> Do you think we can get back to that
place or what do you think?
>> I think it's possible. You do?
>> I think it's going to take a very long
time, but I think it's possible.
>> And I think we have to start by by
trying to snap out of this mindset that
we have to be the world's policeman.
>> Yeah. Like why?
I have relatives in Greece and friends
all over Europe and they ask me the same
question all the time. Why are you guys
doing this?
>> Like like did we really need to
overthrow Libya?
>> Uh Gaddafi rather in Libya.
>> I think a lot of people are don't know
what's going on. They just want their
families to be okay. They don't want
data centers. A lot of people do not
want AI. They don't give a [__] about
it. It's not going to benefit them.
>> Genuinely frightened.
>> Oh, the Pope is frightened. And I'm
trying to get the pope to come and I I
offered that I would go to the Vatican
and talk with the pope. I just want to
wonder I want to learn about what he
thinks.
>> Um
>> the archbishop of the Greek Orthodox
Church just issued an encyclical 100%
supporting everything the pope said on
this.
>> Wow.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. I mean it would be a blessing to
get to talk with him and just learn. I
just want to like be able to like, you
know, share a message, be a part of
Nike. Not me share it, but just be like,
you know, just part of the telephone
game of of helping or being a part of
the message getting out if I can.
>> Yeah.
>> Cuz I do think it's important. We don't
want that. Nobody wants it. 30 people
want it.
>> 100 people want it with a lot of power.
>> Exactly.
>> We don't want it.
>> Yes.
>> Nobody wants it. I Nobody wants it.
>> Yeah. There it is right there. cyclical.
>> Yeah, I read about this. I've read part
of the popes, but I haven't seen this
new one. This is from the um Orthodox
Church.
>> Yeah, the Greek Orthodox Archbishop.
It's uh El Potos is his name endorsing
everything the Pope said about AI. Um
you have a new podcast. Thanks, Sean,
for hanging out. Sorry if I haven't had
the questions at certain points.
>> No, your questions were great and they
cut right to the heart of things. Trying
to get my brain back on track a little
bit. It's just been like a long month.
But um before you do leave, I know you
have a podcast that you're starting your
own finally. Thank you.
>> Finally.
>> You've been on you've been on all of
them, so you have to start your own. And
it's called
>> the briefing room.
>> Yeah. John Kuryaku's Briefing Room.
>> John Kuryaku's Briefing Room.
>> We're going to launch it in about four
weeks. Um if you go to Real John Kuryaku
on YouTube,
>> it'll pop up saying coming soon. Please,
please, please subscribe. And I have
another one too called John Kuryaku's
Dead Drop that's on Apple Podcast and
Spotify. It's just story after story
after story and it's it's been actually
very popular. Been very lucky. We've
gone up to number five in the history
category worldwide.
>> Oh, it's exciting.
>> It's really Yeah, very exciting.
>> Yeah, it's an exciting time. I mean
that's one thing that we also have to
remember is like sure things seem this
way and that way but also it is an ex
like if you can see excitement as like
being of all things and not just things
that seem positive but things that could
seem
>> um to be decided then there is a lot of
excitement and so that's like a nice way
to think about things.
>> Agreed. Um, and you this your book, The
Ultimate God of CIA, skills, tactics,
and techniques. Is there a basic one you
can give us out of the book, man, that's
just something that you can notice about
people when
>> Yeah, the one the the part that I'm
proudest of in this book is the section
on surveillance and surveillance
detection. I took it so seriously that I
actually became a surveillance
instructor at the CIA for the last uh
two years that I was at headquarters.
Um, I'll tell you something that
happened to me when I was in Pakistan. I
was always very very very careful about
my own personal security. And um
I noticed one day I was staying at a at
a guest house, a little 14 room guest
house.
And uh I noticed one day there's a guy
in a motorcycle. He's trying really hard
to stay in my blind spot. And the only
reason I even noticed him was he had a
red motorcycle helmet on. And nobody in
Pakistan wore motorcycle helmets. I
don't even know where you would buy a
motorcycle helmet. So I was like, "Huh,
that's funny." I speed up, he speeds up.
I slow down, he slows down. I change
lanes, he changes lanes. I'm like, "Oh,
this this isn't good." I get to the
entrance to the diplomatic quarter,
which was the part of town where all the
embassies were, and he breaks off. Well,
I work like 14, 15, 16 hours every
single day. I get to work when it's
dark. I leave work when it's dark. And
so I pull out of the diplomatic quarter
and the guy's on me again. And I was
like, "Oh, this is definitely not good."
I was worried about it all night. So the
next morning, I get up at 5:00 in the
morning and I'm taking a different route
to work every day. I'm leaving at a
different time every day. My routes to
work don't make any sense
>> just to make sure I'm not being
followed. And now twice I am being
followed. There's a definition of
surveillance at the CIA. It's multiple
sightings at time and distance. So you
see the person more than once at
different times of the day and at
different places.
So, we have a database. So, I put in the
database when I first arrive. I think
I'm under surveillance. It's a
motorcycle. Here's the license number.
This is a description of the guy. He's
wearing a red helmet.
Next day, I get up at 5:00 in the
morning. I just open the door, a crack.
I look up and down the street. I don't
see anybody. So, they they had assigned
us these like poles, these retracting
poles with a mirror on the bottom. So, I
look under my car. I don't see any
explosives or tracking devices or
anything. So, you got to be careful, you
know. So, I get in the car. I go like
two blocks and the guy's on me again.
So, I finally get to the office and um I
waited for the security officer to come
in and I said, "Listen, I'm under
surveillance. I'm 100% sure I'm under
surveillance." I told him about the
three sightings. He's like, "Oo, this
isn't good." I said, "I know." He said,
"We have to wait until the chief comes
in." So, finally the chief comes in
around seven. And I said, "I'm under
surveillance, 100% certain." So I
explained to him the three different
sightings. And he's like, "Well,
you know what you have to do." And I
said, "I I know." He goes, "You never
popped your cherry that way, did you?
Let's shoot somebody."
>> Uhhuh. And I said, "Nope. Never needed
to." He's like, "Well, we're going to
have we're going to have teams out
there. Don't worry. We're going to have
guys all around you. You're not going to
be alone." I'm like, "Okay, all right."
I was very worried. So, I get back to my
office. My office, it was me. I was the
only staff officer and six retirees who
had all been in the senior intelligence
service. Every one of the six had either
been the chief or deputy chief of
Neareastern operations. One had been the
assistant deputy director of the CIA,
>> but they all came back after 9/11 for
patriotic reasons. But if you're a
contractor, you can't be the chief. So,
they all worked for me, right? And word
got around. They're like, "Don't worry,
buddy. We're all going to be out there.
Don't worry about a thing." I'm like,
"I'm very worried."
That afternoon, I have a meeting at a
safe house that we shared with the
Pakistani intelligence service. We
interrogated a prisoner. And I get up to
leave and I don't know what possessed me
to stop. And I turned and I said,
"General Muhammad, are you following
me?" And he says, "No." Why? I said,
"Because I'm under surveillance. I'm
100% sure that I'm under surveillance
and I'm going to kill the guy this
afternoon." And he's like, "No, it's not
us. I never saw him again."
>> So weeks later, we heard that a bunch of
them were sitting around the table and
one of them said, "The new guy, Kiryaku,
he's a nice guy." And everybody's like,
"Yeah, he's a very nice guy." And then
one of them said, "You know what?
Nobody's that nice. He's probably being
nice just to to trick us into a sense of
complacency. We don't know what he's
doing when he's not here. He's probably
spying on us. I wasn't.
But they put the worst surveillance
officer in the entire Pakistani
intelligence service on me. So instead
of two blocks back, he's right there in
my blind spot. And it was only because I
stopped before I got to the door that
afternoon and asked General Muhammad
>> if they were following me. If
>> that's the only reason that guy's not in
the ground today.
>> I was going to kill him that afternoon.
Oh yes, I was.
>> Dang, John about to pop off.
>> I was convinced he was going to kill me.
>> That big guy.
>> Mhm.
>> That's crazy, bro.
>> Dang, dude. I think everybody wants to
shoot somebody,
but they don't let you. I worked with a
guy, great friend, go to the same
church, from the same men's group.
>> They don't let you.
>> And he's a psychiatrist. [laughter]
Sorry, you made me laugh. He's a
psychiatrist. And he said to me, "I find
it fascinating that you don't have
PTSD."
And I said, "Is that good or bad?" He
said, "From a psychiatric point of
view." And I said, "Yeah." He goes, "Not
good."
I said, "I wasn't afraid of those
people, Steve. I was not afraid of
them." Yeah. It is interesting, man. the
things that we hold, what's going on
inside of us, you know, how it comes
out, what gets figured out,
>> you know,
>> you just never know. You never know
what's going to bother you. You never
know what's going to stick in your mind
and bother you and fester for years. It
happens.
>> Yeah.
The stories, man, ain't about just
making a story, you know? I mean, you
seem like a kind of guy that likes to
make a story, you know?
>> I like telling these stories and people
say
>> and living a story, though. I mean,
>> oh, yeah. Yeah. Oh, listen. I'm an
adrenaline junkie. I don't know what I
would do if I didn't have these stories
in my past. I'd be like, "Oh my god." My
first wife, she's like, "I want to move
back to Ohio and I want you to sell car
insurance with my cousin Dean." I said,
"I would rather cut my throat than move
to Ohio and sell insurance with your
cousin.
>> I'd rather join the Aryan Brotherhood in
prison."
>> Seriously. Seriously.
>> And you did. And I did.
>> So I take a look [laughter]
insurance next time.
>> Yeah. Next life.
>> John, tell your son I said what's up.
That you mentioned on the way in.
>> Thank you, Max. Max telling myself
what's up. And uh is Kiraaku is it
Greek?
>> Greek.
>> Was thinking about that. Um you have the
new book, you have the new podcast.
Thank you so much for your time,
brother.
>> Thank you. Thanks for the invitations.
Great.
>> Great to meet you. You too, man. It's a
pleasure. Thank you. Thanks.
>> Now I'm just floating on the breeze and
I feel I'm falling like these leaves. I
[music] must be corner stone.
Oh, but when I [music] reach that
ground, I'll share this peace of mind I
found. I can feel it in my
[music and singing] bones.
But it's going to take